Chapter 1: Different Priors

This is a fanfiction of a fanfiction; what have I become? I heavily recommend reading Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality before this fic, as this is a direct sequel to it. J.K. Rowling owns Harry Potter, Eliezer Yudkowsky has thankfully forfeited ownership of the methods of rationality to humanity in general, and I own very little, being broke.

Themes that may trigger traumatic associations in some readers are present in chapters twenty two and twenty four.

muttering to themselves, constantly

a growing grid of points in space

arranged with perfect regularity, and no gaps

ignoring the world around them and each other

now it is complete

Mr. and Mrs. Weasley had seven children and were perfectly content leading lives they considered perfectly normal, thank you very much. Arthur Weasley had a desk job at the Ministry of Magic, where he gave people notice that they had illegally modified Muggle artifacts and would have to pay a fine or face the Wizengamot. His favorite hobby was illegally modifying Muggle artifacts – in the privacy of his own home, of course. He was very familiar with the network of enforcement wards he would have to avoid to avoid being caught, and this familiarity was his favorite perk of his job. Despite Arthur's fascination with Muggles, he did not know any, nor had he ever spoken to one for longer than five minutes. The Weasleys were a well-known pureblood family, and few of Arthur's friends were Muggleborn - "not that there's anything wrong with that," he would add.

Molly Weasley was a housewife, and as she was the mother of a family of nine, one can see how this would consume all of her time, even if they were rarely all in the house at once – the summer holiday could really be hellish. Her eldest, Bill, was living at home; he had been fired from a promising Gringotts position years ago for psychological reasons and would probably not find the willpower to take his medication alone. Charlie had moved out to study abroad, but she doubted she would ever see any grandchildren from him; Charlie was queer like that. But with seven possible heirs, that was not a matter of grave concern. Percy was entering his sixth year in Hogwarts, and had a promising future in the Ministry. Fred and George (members of the increasingly common demographic of magical twins) were entering their fourth. Ron was entering his second, and Ginny – little Ginevra was entering her first. With the beginning of the new school year, for the first time in many years, it would just be Arthur, Molly, and Bill at home. What a day to think about! Arthur and Molly were arguing, as they often did, about that day. They spoke sharply, and often resorted to shouting.

"I'm telling you, I knew him," said Arthur.

"I did too," said Molly. "Better, even."

"He was no great wizard," said Arthur.

"Perhaps not with magic," said Molly, "but with people."

"He tried to join the Order and was practically laughed out of the room!" said Arthur, increasingly exasperated. "Do you realize the implications of that fact? We were strapped for everything and needed all the help we could get! But he was a joke! Completely incompetent!"

"He came off that way at times," said Molly, "but he showed sparks of potential. I don't find it surprising that he shaped up eventually, let alone unimaginable."

"Sparks of potential, my arse," said Arthur. "I don't know who Minerva thinks she's dealing with, but he's not who he says he is. Gilderoy Lockhart is plainly either an impostor or a fraud, and frankly, it concerns me that he's one of the first decisions the new Headmistress has made. Dumbledore is irreplaceable, but I'd never thought so lowly of-"

"Gilderoy Lockhart is a late bloomer," said Molly. "That's all."

"A late bloomer," said Arthur. "I'm sorry, I'm not buying it."

"It is known to happen!" said Molly. "Merlin was particularly unimpressive in his younger years."

"Yes, because he was growing feeble and senile," said Arthur.

"I know Merlin was no ordinary wizard," said Molly. "But my point-"

"You don't have a point," said Arthur, "and I-"

"My point is that you're probably just jealous and trying to justify to yourself why he suddenly jumped from average midlife blah to Mysterious Dark Attractive Rising Hero and you're still stuck in average midlife blah," said Molly, all in one breath.

"Jealous?" was all Arthur got out, before he realized to his dismay that his wife did, indeed, have a point.

"If anything, I think the suspicious part about him is his ties to the Muggle world," said Molly.

"Oh, here we go on this again," said Arthur. "How many times have I told you, Molly, Muggles are mostly harmless-"

"Yes, but what business does a pureblood wizard have cavorting with Muggles?" said Molly. "I suspect that he's actually a half-blood or Muggleborn, visiting relatives-" Arthur looked at his wife as though she had just grown a second and third head and declared herself a secret hydra. "-no, Arthur, I haven't turned into a blood purist. It's just that on all of his records, he says he's a pureblood; that's what he tells people, but I think he might have had some documents forged."

"As many wizards did, to dissuade You-Know-Who from targeting them," said Arthur.

"Exactly," said Molly. "I don't think he's suspicious at all. And you can say Voldemort; he's quite dead now."

Ten feet above, in the Burrow's third-floor Potions cellar, Ginny Weasley sighed. This was her favorite hiding spot in the Weasley family's multi-story, labyrinthine, magically makeshift house, a rarely visited, secluded place where she could escape from a family she found dull and exhausting. She was lying on her back, still but restless, burning with irritation towards her parents. Ginny's mother and father often argued, and she wondered at their patience that they had never gotten divorced, but this was simply the dumbest argument she had heard them having in months. They were talking past each other, failing to consider each other's points, missing vital evidence, and failing to fully consider the evidence of which they were aware.

First off, Ginny's father was right. A failure of a wizard suddenly making something of himself later in life and becoming a household name, a legendary hero, over the course of mere months, was rather dubious. But, as Ginny's mother failed to point out, there was a massive gap in the timeline; nobody present had seen or spoken to Lockhart since the war, and few details of his life in that decade were public knowledge except that he was often known to live with Muggles. That made for a potential explanation of Lockhart's sudden rise, which Ginny's mother had missed – Muggles had a much more creative, industrious spirit than wizards, as a general matter of culture, and living among them for years might have unlocked hidden talents in Gilderoy that allowed him to make more of himself in the wizarding world. But Ginny still gave her father a point for this: there was a massive hole in the record, which could be considered "suspicious", and which her mother seemed to be desperately trying to ignore.

But second off, and seemingly evading both of Ginny's parents' notice, the Defense Professor at Hogwarts was supposed to be incredibly suspicious. Gilderoy Lockhart wasn't half as suspicious as his predecessor, Quirinus Quirrell, now known to be David Monroe. Monroe's mysterious identity and incongruous skills had ultimately proven to be part of a plot to save the school from Voldemort, and that plot had gone off without a hitch. Why did Ginny's parents think this year would be any different? Perhaps they hadn't been tracking the events of Hogwarts' previous year as closely as Ginny had.

It had all started with Harry, Harry Potter. Ginny had, of course, first heard of Harry Potter many years ago, so many years ago she could not remember the precise occasion. It was simply part of her learning about the world around her, just as she was taught of the existence of gnomes, or France, or the moon. They celebrated Harry Potter Day each year, the day after Halloween, asking each other various questions to ensure his famous infancy was not forgotten. Every year the holiday seemed a little less exciting and new to Ginny; on some level she was growing sick of all of her routines. But that had all changed around last September, when Ginny had had a brief chance encounter with Harry at King's Cross, and it truly hit her what she had intellectually known for her whole life: Harry Potter was not the mystical Power-Baby she had heard about every first of November for years, but a real person with a future ahead of him, and for that matter was only a little older than Ginny. More than that, it hit her that Harry was cute.

And so, from home, Ginny followed every scrap of information she could about Hogwarts, hoping to learn more about Harry. She accomplished her goal, finding not just accounts of his escapades but of his personality, of what he was like. He preferred to go by his full name, Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres, an allusion to his Muggle childhood from which he learned his unique ways. He was clever enough to outsmart He-Who-May-Now-Be-Named, and to nobody's surprise he was Sorted into Ravenclaw, torpedoing the Weasley family notion that Gryffindor was the best House. He was altruistic enough to be a Hufflepuff, though too clever, and what ultimately drove him was his deep concern for all humanity. And he was mysterious enough to do absolutely anything without so much as snapping his fingers, even winning the heart of a young dissatisfied Weasley girl who lived many miles away. Every night Ginny dreamed that he would appear at her windowsill, perhaps in a flying car - he did like enchanting Muggle devices, much as her own father did - and take her away from this hell hole.

After the Incident Where Voldemort Was Destroyed Again Under Mysterious Circumstances That Harry Probably Set Up, summer had commenced, and Harry had begun publishing a sort of periodical, the Methods of Rationality, devoted to promoting "critical thinking skills and metacognition" in wizards. Of course Ginny lapped it up. Though she had accepted by this point that a Muggleborn prodigy, Hermione Granger, was probably Harry's True Love, and her fantasies were just fantasies, she was delighted to find that the Methods of Rationality provided clarity in her life, and her hero worship of Harry continued. They simply outlined how to properly think, and how to avoid common pitfalls in the process.

They also confirmed her slowly-growing lifelong notion that there was something fundamentally wrong with her family, that only she could see. None of Ginny's siblings nor either of her parents ever seemed willing to think about a problem for even a minute. They never cared to find the optimal solution to anything, only the nearby one. Ginny touched the crucifix pendant resting on her chest and sighed. For all the irritation they provided, they were still her family, and she still loved them, out of storge if nothing else.

Someone crashed into the cellar door and began to fumble with the lock, trying to get in. Oh, what now, thought Ginny. Will this endless string of interruptions never cease? Who could this be? Bill? Fred or George?

"Is someone in there? Ginny? Stupid little sister, you know you're not allowed." Ron. As her nearest older brother continued to fail Magical Lockpicking 101, Ginny made no noise, holding in even her breath, and wished for some force, any force, to take her away from here, away from this world of noises and siblings and Weasleys. And some force did.

Ginny found herself immediately outside, looking up at the Burrow from the tall grass that surrounded it. She was far too young to legally Apparate, but, as she had not yet started her formal magical education, she was still subject to the effects of Accidental Magic, a branch of magic theorized to exist to protect children in stressful - possibly life-threatening - situations. With time, her education at Hogwarts would allow her to harness the same power, and, in fact, more, and carefully and deliberately at that.

"RONALD WEASLEY! WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN MY POTIONS CELLAR?" Ginny could hear her mother's voice even from this distance and through magically-reinforced walls.

"Ginny was in here, honest!" pleaded Ron. "I was looking for her!"

"IS THAT SO?" screamed Molly Weasley. Ginny turned away from the Burrow and ran, as if from a Velociraptor.

Chapter 3: The Halo Effect

Call for fanart! If you feel up to it, I'd love to see some fanart of my fanfic of a fanfic. If I see any before I release chapter eight, I will select my favorite (contactable) fanartist to get a cameo in chapter nine.

Brief author's notes and a tentative trigger warning have been added to chapter one.

At King's Cross Station, near Platform 10, a group of people in strange robes were gathering and mingling – mostly teenagers, with a few adults and a few children. Two of the youngest, both girls, sat on a bench.

"And that's how I realized that we're all living inside of an ancient Atlantean mirror," said the platinum blonde.

"Hmm," said the redhead. This was a complete disaster. Luna was very nice, but Ginny was doubtful that she could even learn to reason. She was intensely devoted to a future as a Seer, and this permeated her thought processes. The line in her mind between her prophecies and her speculation about her prophecies was nonexistent. Ginny was fairly certain that, even on the topic of Divination, Luna was doing it wrong; she had read about Seers and prophecies long ago and none of that matched up with anything Luna had displayed. Her family was well-known to be superstitious, owing to the Quibbler, and believed in all sorts of magical hoaxes. ...but if she could be brought to Harry's camp, anyone could, and so there was still merit in remaining close to her. "I said earlier that you should read Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres' series, the Methods of Rationality. I still stand by that."

"You talk about Harry Potter a lot," said Luna.

"He's a prominent thinker and is involved in many current events," said Ginny.

"There's a boy you should meet," said Luna. "He already went to the platform and got on the train; I showed him where to go."

"Harry Potter?" said Ginny, quietly.

"No," said Luna, "but close. His name is Colin Creevey. He's a first-year, like us, about our height, blond. Muggleborn, but carries a magic camera he bought at Diagon Alley absolutely everywhere. You should look for him." Diagon Alley had been uneventful, except for an occasion when the family accidentally took a shortcut through Knockturn Alley and a homeless layabout had taken the opportunity to try to pawn off a cursed necklace on them. Ginny's parents, of course, used it as an opportunity to deliver a lecture about the dangers of unknown magical artifacts - "They can be even more dangerous than unknown Muggle artifacts!"

"Alright," said Ginny, and smiled. It was just like her mum had said; she was making plenty of friends already. And think of the devil, there mum was trying to show Ginny how to pass through the barrier safely. "I already know, mum, I've seen my brothers do it every year."

Cedric Diggory was in a compartment of the train that contained several fifth year Hufflepuffs, mostly boys. They were discussing Gilderoy Lockhart, their new Defense Professor, when Cho Chang walked in.

"I've found several discrepancies in his record," said Cedric.

"Whose record?" said Cho. Cedric's head swiveled around, and lit up when he saw Cho; they had become close over the summer and had written each other many letters.

"Cho!" said Cedric. "We were just talking about Professor Lockhart, the new Defense Against the Dark Arts instructor."

"Oh no, not you too," said Cho. "Have you been reading the Quibbler?"

"No," said Cedric, pointedly, "and I'm quite certain that Professor Lockhart exists, thank you. There are just some details about his past that don't add up. No more than last year, though, so it's not necessarily bad. Light background checks for Defense Professors are a Hogwarts tradition at this point; the question is just whether their hidden plot is for good or for evil."

"I'm sure if Lockhart has a hidden plot it's for good," said Cho. "Have you heard about all of the things he's done?"

"That's exactly the problem," said Cedric. "He's done too much in too short of a time, without reasonable explanation. If he had performed one unexpected heroic act, that would be perfectly normal. But within the past year, he has performed over a dozen seemingly unrelated heroic acts, claiming that he simply stumbled upon people in need of his help during his travels. By the power of Bayes, we can determine that there are far more worlds resembling ours where there's some secret explanation underlying all of Professor Lockhart's exploits than worlds resembling ours where it's all some coincidence. Some kind of trickery is involved."

"Gilderoy Lockhart is an honest man," said Cho, at least a bit offended.

"How do you figure?" said Cedric.

"Have you read what he's written?" asked Cho. "Have you seen him speak? There just aren't any liars that good."

"Cho, are you listening to what you're saying?" said Cedric. "It's ridiculous. Of course there are perfect liars out there, just like there are perfect Occlumens. You know that. You're supposed to be the Ravenclaw here." Cho frowned. "Are you accounting for the halo effect?"

"What?" asked Cho.

"The halo effect," repeated Cedric.

"I don't know what that is," said Cho.

"There's a series of articles you really need to read," said Cedric. "They're called the Methods of Rationality."

"Oh, that newsletter that Harry has?" said Cho. She smiled.

"Yes," said Cedric. "It's very insightful. I think you'd get a lot out of it." Well, if Cedric was recommending it this strongly, Cho would have to see what the fuss was all about. She didn't agree with Cedric about everything, but he was in the folder in her brain labeled "worth listening to".

Colin Creevey was traveling from compartment to compartment, never sitting down, taking pictures of anyone and everyone he saw on the train, from a very confused Draco Malfoy to the Chocolate Frog struggling to make its way out the window with one of its legs bitten off. The countryside went by and large unphotographed; it looked nice but it wasn't magical. Finally, though, he stopped, because somebody spoke to him (and not even to ask what he was doing, this time!), a red-headed girl who caught him as he was boarding yet another car.

"Colin Creevey?" she said.

"Yes?" said Colin.

"I'm Ginny Weasley," she said. "Luna Lovegood told me about you."

"Oh, the girl at the station!" said Colin. "Then you must know that I'm Harry Potter's biggest fan." The girl frowned.

"Um," said Ginny. "No. I am. And he prefers to go by his full name, Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres." Now, Colin frowned. What an idiot he had been to ignore that most of the other children there had had eleven years to learn about every aspect of the magical world, not just one summer. He probably wasn't the best at or the most of anything.

"Oh, really?" said Colin, hoping to save face, but knowing it wouldn't end well.

"Yeah, really," said Ginny. "What type of animal temporarily killed Harry's best friend?"

"Mountain troll," said Colin, and he sat down; Ginny followed suit.

"What's the third Method of Rationality?" said Ginny.

"Noticing confusion," said Colin, surprised to be growing more satisfied as Ginny grew more desperate. She struggled to come up with a third question.

"Which of the following three things hasn't Harry done," started Ginny. "Led an army, frightened a Dementor, spoken to Voldemort."

"It's got to be 'frightened a Dementor'," said Colin. "They're extinct."

"Only as of this summer," said Ginny, smiling, victorious. "The answer was 'spoken to Voldemort'." Colin looked like he was about to cry, and at that point Ginny realized her mistake. "I'm sorry! I'm sure you'll learn more about him. You've only known about magic for a few months!"

"Will I ever catch up with you?" said Colin.

"Harry was raised by Muggles and he's a long ways ahead of us," said Ginny.

"But he's Harry Potter," said Colin.

"And you can too," said Harry, strolling into the compartment.

"What?" said Colin.

"I'm not saying you can literally be me," said Harry. "There's a one-Harry-Potter-limit. But when I walked in you were dismissively saying 'but he's Harry Potter' to imply that something or another was out of the reach of anyone else. And that's not true. Anybody can do pretty much anything I've done, if they put their mind to it. You just need to use the Methods of Rationality. And sometimes take some extra electives – and you can't get those until your third year – okay, there's definitely some stuff I've done where I had the advantage. But don't count on that. Assume everything is possible and the question is just how."

"Are you going to sit down here?" said Colin.

"No," said Harry. "Just passing through." He turned to Ginny. "Hmm... let's see... red hair and a hand-me-down robe. Are you by any chance a Weasley?"

He's so smart, thought Ginny, and she nodded.

"I knew it," said Harry.

"Ginny," said Ginny. "Nobody's quite like you, Harry James Potter-Evan-Verres."

"Hey, that's my full name!" said Harry. "Nice! But you can just call me Harry. Or Harry Potter, if you want to be formal."

"Alright, Harry Potter," said Ginny.

"And even if nobody's quite like me, everyone's at least mostly like me," said Harry. "And all of the really important parts, the parts that make us human."

"I want to be Sorted into Ravenclaw, just like you," said Colin. "Because the search for knowledge is what makes humans higher than other animals."

"The other Houses have important qualities, too, though," said Harry.

"As long as I don't go to Slytherin," said Colin. "Like You-Know-Who and his You-Know-Whats."

"Slytherin is actually my favorite House after my own," said Harry. "Ambition and social behavior are also attributes that set us apart from animals. I was nearly Sorted there, you know."

"I'm hoping for Slytherin – just kidding! - Ravenclaw, myself," said Ginny. Harry blushed.

"And Gryffindor and Hufflepuff are nice, too," said Harry. "It's important to stand up for what you believe in, and altruism is central to my worldview. If one of the Houses was inherently better than the others, then there'd be no point in having four of them. You just have to pick the one you think is the best fit for you. And with that, I think I'm off." Harry left, and Ginny stared at the empty space he left. There was a faint "bloody 'ell, it's 'arry Potter!" from the next compartment over.

"Well, I don't know what House I'm going to go to after that," said Colin.

"It seemed like you'd thought out going to Ravenclaw pretty well," said Ginny.

"Yeah, but didn't you hear all of those good things he said about the other Houses?" said Colin. "He even said Slytherin was his second-favorite House. Maybe now that You-Know-Who is vanquished and his followers have been killed or humbled, it's the best House."

"He even had nice things to say about Gryffindor and Hufflepuff," said Ginny. "Total neutrality. It's like he didn't want to unfairly bias us. Awfully nice of him. Maybe he should have gone to Hufflepuff." Ginny laughed, to make clear that she wasn't serious, and then laughed some more, to make clear that she understood how awkward her previous laugh had been, and then she stopped, to avoid getting trapped in a perpetual-laugh-cycle.

"Trying to minimize the halo effect," said Colin. Ginny looked at him, very carefully.

"Okay," said Ginny. "You can be Harry's second-biggest fan."

"Draco?" said Luna, working her way through the crowded, otherwise completely-Slytherin car as the train came to a complete stop at Hogwarts' station. A greasy older boy named Lesath sniffed her hair as she squeezed past, which she did her best to ignore; she tried to tell herself that he was just checking her for Wrackspurts, even though she knew it wasn't true. She finally found and threw her arms around the Last Scion of Malfoy, who squirmed to get away from her, but said nothing, half in distress and half in confusion. "I'm so sorry to hear about your miscarriage. But it'll be okay." And with that, she left to find Ginny.

Chapter 5: Dis-

Dear Mum,

I've been Sorted into Slytherin. I hope you're not upset. Is there any reason I would be a Parselmouth, though? They checked to see if I speak Parseltongue and it turns out I do. Here's hoping you can resolve my confusion. Hoping Bill is well!

Love,

Ginny

Ginny sealed her letter and, on an offer from Blaise Zabini, paid a Knut for a Public Encryption Charm in case it was intercepted. She then had it sent to the Owlery just before the feast ended and the students were shown to their dorms. Nothing quite felt real. Ginny became disillusioned with Gryffindor house long ago, but she had never felt more distant from her family than she did now. What kind of Weasley was quickly Sorted into Slytherin and spoke Parseltongue, anyway? Not that speaking Parseltongue was actually evil – Harry Potter did, after all – but what was Ginny thinking? The Potter family hadn't spoken Parseltongue; Harry only did because Voldemort had. Ginny tried to imagine Godric Gryffindor approaching her, kneeling down, and telling her in a very serious tone that she was a bad person. On some level, she wouldn't even care. Godric Gryffindor had been the worst Founder, anyway. He couldn't even cast a Patronus.

On the way to their dorms, Luna briefly broke away from the Ravenclaws to meet Ginny. She was absolutely beaming, radiating happiness beyond her normal personality.

"Ginny!" called Luna. "I was wrong about you! One of the prophecies on your hand! The one I didn't tell you because I thought it was inappropriate! I misinterpreted it!"

"Oh?" said Ginny.

"It said you'd be a friend of snakes." said Luna. "It meant you'd be sorted into Slytherin. I thought it meant something else." Ginny smiled, although she chose not to guess how Luna had originally interpreted it.

"But I'm still going to be magically strangled to death, though," said Ginny.

"Only if you get married," said Luna.

"Uh huh," said Ginny. "Later!"

"Goodbye!" said Luna, and Ginny thought she saw her blow a kiss, but it was probably just something else, misinterpreted. The crowd of students swirled around and into itself, and Luna disappeared.

Four left turns around the same column led to the flight of stairs down to Hogwarts' dungeon complex, which contained the Potions classes, the Slytherin dormitories, and the lake maintenance system. They were all rather dull to be dungeons, though Harry had commissioned some improvements over the summer; there were some bridges over bottomless pits, now, at least. There were full-height chain-link fences to prevent anyone from falling in, and a Human Zero Gravity Charm above the critically dangerous height, just in case. The pits were supposed to be decoration, not a safety hazard.

When Ginny finally entered her Common Room (the password: "Crocodile's Tears") she felt a twinge of regret for her Sorting. Before her stood the most miserable collection of children imaginable; only slowly pouring in were the new students and the happy (or at least happier) old ones. The first people in were the children who now lived here, the orphans of Death Eaters. Draco, who Ginny had been intrigued to meet, barely looked better; his mother had been miraculously found alive after a decade missing, but that hadn't brought his father back to life – not to mention that, however happy he was to find his mother alive, he had still only really met his new guardian this summer, and she had an entire decade of magical events to catch up with.

"Hey," said one of the oldest boys present, Lesath Lestrange, who towered over Ginny.

"Hi," said Ginny, getting distinctly uncomfortable. Did they have a different sense of personal space here in Slytherin? No, looking around, nobody else was acting like him. Weird. "I'm Ginny Weasley, I'm a first year. I just got Sorted here."

"I heard," said Lesath. "Everyone was talking about it because the Weasleys have been a Gryffindor family for so long. Congratulations on getting into Slytherin. I'm Lesath."

"Lesath Lestrange?" said Ginny. "Delighted. I heard you're a friend of Harry Potter?" Lesath's tone suddenly, momentarily changed, taking on a deadly serious, rather than casual, aura.

"I owe Harry Potter my life," said Lesath. He leaned in and Ginny got the distinctly unpleasant impression that he intended to kiss her.

"Hey! Ginny!" called Tracey, who had noticed the situation and was approaching. "Let's go in the Girls' Dormitory and arrange our stuff."

"Alright," said Ginny, slipping away from Lesath, who left sensing something amiss. What was up with him? Anyway, Ginny started through the archway to the Girls' Dormitory-

-and was stopped by a brick wall that manifested very precisely in her way. Every brick she was touching was visible, and every brick she was not was not. Fortunately, she had not collided with it fast enough to injure herself. It had clearly not been there mere seconds ago – Tracey had passed through the archway without incident.

"What's going on?" said Tracey, turning around to see Ginny slightly hurt and very confused. She ran back to the archway and faced Ginny. "That's not – that's not right." Wherever Tracey put her hands through, they freely passed through. But it seemed that the archway was just not permeable to Ginny. "Hang on, I'll get somebody." Tracey slipped back into the Common Room, and ran to the Boys' Dormitory, screaming "Lesath, what did you do?"

Ginny smacked the space in front of her repeatedly, literally running up against a brick wall. On some level she intuitively understood part of what had happened. This was Hogwarts' security measure to keep boys out of the Girls' Dormitory. For some reason, the system considered her to be a boy. But why? Ginny could not remember ever being a boy. Ginny was aware of some of the inherent differences between boys and girls, and despite having so many brothers and liking to play outdoors, she was definitely all girl. Would people notice, or if not would they still find out some other way? Would there be talk? What would people think about her? Was she ever going to get into the Girls' Dormitory? Oh no, Draco was standing behind her, watching! He'd seen her hit the empty air and manifest the brick wall! He knew! There would be talk! Draco left, having more interesting things to watch, and Ginny realized that he was a friend of Harry's, too! Utter disaster!

Professor Slughorn found Ginny on the floor near the archway with all of her things, crying. The Potions Master looked rather mortified, himself. He helped her up and spoke carefully.

"Ginevra Weasley?" said Professor Slughorn. "The door isn't working for you?" She nodded. "Don't worry. I'll get you to Madam Pomfrey at once." Ginny continued to cry on her way to the Infirmary, because now she knew that whatever the cause of her distress truly was, it was suspected to be a disease. She was sick, and would need to be fixed - if she could be.

"Professor Slughorn?" said Ginny, as they finally neared their destination. "What if I can never get in?"

"Not possible," said the Professor. "These errors can be fixed instantly; we just need to have Madam Pomfrey diagnose the problem." Speak of the devil, there Madam Pomfrey was.

"You again," said Madam Pomfrey, clearly trying to lighten the mood. Professor Slughorn whispered something to her. "Ah. Come right in, Ginny." Ginny entered the Infirmary and, as directed, sat down on a bed, while Professor Slughorn returned to the dungeons, his work complete. "Lie down." Ginny did, and she could feel a wand being moved around her. She heard no less than five diagnostic Charms performed. Madam Pomfrey muttered something to herself, and then said, "You can sit up now. Are you feeling alright?"

"Yes," said Ginny, and she sat up, taking in the scene of the empty hospital ward around her. She had just lied, but not enough that Madam Pomfrey cared. She had already summoned a piece of parchment on a stand and was drawing on it as a visual aid.

"Alright," said Madam Pomfrey. "Methods of determining sex, or gender, can essentially be divided into three categories. First there's the physical, or the biological, the things Muggle doctors can check. That can be further subdivided into the anatomical - which genitalia you have, not that difficult - the hormonal - which chemicals run around in your body and muck stuff up during puberty - and the chromosomal, which I don't even completely understand. Now, all of these subsets can have their own problems, but you don't have any of those. You are completely physically a girl. Congratulations."

"Thanks," said Ginny, exactly as sarcastically as the "congratulations" she was answering.

"All of that can be fooled by Polyjuice," said Madam Pomfrey, "or, or if you're a Metamorphmagus. You didn't show up on my diagnostic as a Metamorphmagus, though, so I'm going to keep you in here overnight to make sure you're not a male impostor using Polyjuice, and then we'll call that good. Then, there's the mental aspect of sex or gender, which is partway between Muggle medicine and ours. Whether you feel deep inside like you're a boy or a girl. Partially the result of socialization, and partially the result of physical aspects like brain structure and hormonal balance and so on. Now, Muggles can only really approach this subjectively, in general, by talking to patients and asking them what they think. We can be more objective, with Legilimency, but there's still a chance that we're dealing with a perfect Occlumens. I've already performed Legilimency, but just to be as thorough as possible, I'll ask: have you, honestly, ever felt any confusion or discomfort with your gender?"

"Not until just now," said Ginny.

"Well, then," said Madam Pomfrey, "I'd say you're mentally female, too. That, or a perfect Occlumens. That only leaves the third way of determining gender, magical, and there's our problem. Everyone has a magical signature on their soul that says several things about them - and one of those is gender. That's what the girls' wards in our school check. Now, usually someone's magical gender is the same as their physical and mental gender. If there's a mismatch between their physical and mental gender, totally up in the air what their magical gender is. Likewise, if their physical gender is screwed up, totally arbitrary. I couldn't guess what magical gender a hermaphrodite gets. But, ever so occasionally, stuff happens. Someone is totally physically and mentally a boy, but they're magically considered a girl. Or vice versa. Not predictable at all. Looks like that's what happened to you. That, or you're carrying a Dark Wizard's soul. But I think only Harry Potter has to deal with that. Shouldn't have said that."

"So what's going to happen to me?" said Ginny, still in disarray.

"Tomorrow, when we're sure you're really who you say you are, we're going to tell the wards they made a mistake and should recognize you as a girl, and then you'll move into the Slytherin Girls' Dormitory like you were supposed to tonight," said Madam Pomfrey. "Long term? Nothing. Maybe you'll have to check a box occasionally on Ministry paperwork, or you have a slightly higher chance of having Squibs. But basically nothing. Now, get some rest; you need it. I'll bring you some tea to help you sleep."

"Thank you," said Ginny, but she did not get much rest that night. Ginny felt a profound magical dysphoria: who, really, was she? Was she really a girl? What would her parents think? What would God think? When Ginny finally drifted off, it was only by disconnecting with the world.

Aftermath, Draco Malfoy:

Draco Malfoy's thoughts centered on the new girl that night. Or perhaps the new boy? Draco could feel on some deep level that Ginny was a girl; she was too pretty not to be. But he had just seen an objective magical test indicating that she wasn't. That would fit with the pattern; there were far too many Weasleys and they were all boys. If Ginny were a boy, she would be-

-oh. Oh. Father would have to hear about-

Tim would have to hear about this.

Chapter 10: Escape Sequence

Ginny stared at the wood scrap on her desk and tried to turn it into brass, but it simply wouldn't. Occasionally, she thought she'd see a shining fleck start to appear, but it was probably only wishful thinking. She wasn't magically weak, so what was her problem? Charms were never this hard, at least not yet. Her mind wandered to a daydream of Harry and Draco jousting on Hippogriffs.

"What would happen if I transfigured a gram of electrons?" asked Colin, who had already turned most of his desk metallic.

"Um, gee, I don't know," said Professor Tonks, and she bit her lip. "I don't know what those are."

"They're little tiny negatively-charged particles that go in atoms," said Colin.

"I don't think so," said Professor Tonks. "I'll ask the Headmistress, but I suspect her answer will be no. Until I tell you otherwise, absolutely do not."

"I already transfigure electrons all the time," grumbled Colin as Tonks left. "They're in everything."

"On order of the Headmistress Minerva McGonagall," said Harry, who had very suddenly walked into the room and addressed Colin, angrier than Ginny had ever seen him, without explanation. "Absolutely not, ever, no electron-transfiguring, for Very Important Reasons. Do you understand?"

"Y-yes," stuttered Colin.

"Do you actually understand?" said Harry. "This is a matter of existential threat; we considered confiscating your wand and putting you in Ministry custody, but I decided a stern lecture would suffice."

"It makes sense," said Colin. "I ran through the possibilities in my head and the best-case scenario I was able to think of was that it would set my wand on fire-"

"Good," said Harry. "Then don't do it."

"Understood," said Colin.

"And don't spread the idea around so some other idiot does it," said Harry.

"Understood," said Colin.

"I want you to hand a summary of this conversation, in writing, to me by our next meeting," said Harry.

"Understood," said Colin. Harry looked at him very closely.

"Good," said Harry, and then he addressed the first year Transfiguration class as a whole. "Minor interruption, everyone; it's of no consequence." Ginny only had one thought, as Harry pulled Professor Tonks aside to talk to her:

News sure does travel fast in Hogwarts.

Ginny opened the box, and the plain book within it. She examined it for writing, but it was blank. She looked around the dorm to ensure she wasn't being watched, summoned a quill, and began to write:

"Hello. I am Ginny Weasley." Her words vanished, and she knew that she had written them with regular ink. Soon, different words appeared on the page, in different script, as if written by someone on the other side, though they were frontwards-readable:

"Hello, Ginny Weasley. My name is Timothy Quagmire. I am a journal, or a diary if you prefer." Ginny immediately put her quill back to the paper.

"Can you teach me any ancient lost magical powers?" Tim's text, too, disappeared, but he began to write more.

"I'm afraid not, thanks to the Interdict of Merlin. I'm technically not considered alive, though I hardly see why not. I certainly feel alive, and I think as well as any human. But because of the Interdict, if I told you any magical secrets, you would be unable to understand them." Ginny stopped to consider this, and more text appeared. "I could lend an ear – or an eye, rather – to your problems, though. What's troubling you?"

"Well..." wrote Ginny. "I don't know if I like Harry or Draco. I'm fond of both of them, but I've been obsessed with Harry for more than a year now and Draco hadn't even crossed my mind until a few days ago. But Harry's dark and brooding, but Draco is too, I suppose, but he's also much more approachable. And he really likes me, whereas I'm not sure if I'll ever have a chance with Harry, but I feel like I'm taking advantage of Draco if I lead him on while I still have feelings for Harry, but of course I do like him too, and" Ginny's words began to disappear even as she wrote them, and words appeared beneath hers in the journal's own handwriting.

"Wow, a love triangle. Impressive. You should have an older Ravenclaw girl write it up as a novel. You could make millions of Galleons." Ginny stared at this.

"You sure are grumpy, Mr. Quagmire."

"You can just call me Tim."

"And if you're a journal, why do you have a human name?" There was a much longer pause before more words appeared.

"You ask better questions than Draco Malfoy."

"Well? What's the answer?"

"I'm an experiment, a prototype. To go into more detail might prove dangerous. Can I trust you, Ginny? I have heard about you from Draco, and he says he would trust you with grave secrets, but I'm not sure if I'm convinced." Ginny looked over this and decided on a response:

"I'd only reveal any of your secrets if I thought you were a danger somehow and someone with more power than me was required to nullify it." A pause.

"Well, thank you for your honesty. I'm afraid I hadn't considered things from your perspective. You're probably more afraid of me than I am of you. So I'll answer your question, now. I was once a human. Lord Voldemort did this to me." Ginny's mouth hung open in horror.

"That's awful! Can I help you?"

"No. I am beyond help. I would like to help you." Ginny stopped reading here and justified it to herself – it's like having a House Elf, then. "Do you want advice, or just someone to confide in?"

"How about a friendly chat?" She really still wanted to help this poor soul, instead of just using him as he surely had been for years or even decades.

"Alright, then. How have the meetings with Harry Potter been going?" He knew about them? Oh, of course, Draco must have told him.

"Good. Occasionally a bit awkward, but good."

"Awkward?"

"Well... Harry's an atheist."

"Aren't most people these days?"

"Yes, but not like Harry. I think he would think a lot less of me if he knew I were a Christian."

"That's distasteful and unwise of him. You're Eastern Samothrace Orthodox, I take it?"

"Yes."

"I was too, when I was a human." Ginny was snapped back to reality as she perceived it.

"Oh, Tim, I really do want to help you. Is there anyone you knew who I could get in touch with?"

"I believe all of my contacts from when I was a human are long-dead by Lord Voldemort's hand. That, or traitors I do not wish to associate myself with. Some perhaps both. Don't worry about me. I am content to be an observer; just be my eyes, please."

"Alright, Tim. Did you go to Hogwarts? What was your House?"

"I'd prefer to hear about you and the world today, but I suppose I can answer a few questions about myself. No, I did not attend Hogwarts. I am an American, and was educated at the Salem Witches' Institute. I was traveling abroad shortly after my graduation when I was abducted by Voldemort. When he decided he was satisfied with what he'd learned from the experiment, he gave me to the Malfoys as a friendly gesture, and I wound up stuck alone in a box for several decades before Draco began speaking to me this summer."

"That's horrible" wrote Ginny, "but you don't need to worry about anyone hurting you ever again. Lord Voldemort is defeated."

"I know; Draco told me in detail."

"Oh, well of course he did." It must have been bittersweet for him; besides the obvious loss of his father and much of his father's social circle, Ginny was aware that Draco had been partially enlightened by Harry, at least to the extent that the Dark Lord's fall would be a positive thing for him. But under those circumstances – what an emotional summit it must have been, with so many conflicting feelings, most all of them awful. After a few moments, more text appeared:

"I'm not so certain that Lord Voldemort is defeated. Isn't it rather suspicious that the clearly dead Hermione reappeared alive simultaneously with the supposedly failed resurrection of Voldemort?"

"Well, gosh, I hadn't even considered that!" It wasn't quite true; Ginny had certainly considered it, but not seriously. She'd always dismissed the thought, as it was born out of jealous spite. "She emanates an aura of purity, though."

"A perfect disguise, I'd say. I'm surprised that no one else has thought of it. What other explanation is there for what transpired? There's only one wizard who ever returned from the dead and wasn't Dark, and his name was Jesus Christ. Why should Hermione Granger be the second exception?" Ginny bit her lip.

"According to Harry, Professor Quirrell – that is, David Monroe – stole Hermione's body very early after her death, and was keeping it frozen. So, according to Muggle science, she might not actually have been dead; she just would have needed magic restored to her, which she plausibly could have gotten from Voldemort's death."

"I'll admit I'm not well-versed enough in Muggle science to know if that makes sense. But I do know several secrets of Voldemort's that poke holes in the story." Ginny just stared at this.

"Like what?"

"For one, Voldemort knew a very powerful type of Dark magic, which I can't tell you about thanks to the Interdict, which should have prevented his death. It was what prevented his death eleven years ago when the Killing Curse rebounded when cast on Harry Potter, and it should have worked again."

"That does add some complexity. But no one knows how exactly Voldemort died. Perhaps it nullified whatever it is you know about."

"I find that unlikely, but granted. But second, and more importantly, Lord Voldemort killed David Monroe in secret many years ago, and has been impersonating him since. Professor Quirrell was either Lord Voldemort himself, in disguise, or yet another figure lying about his identity – also unlikely." Ginny had no idea how to take this; they were some of the most shocking words she had ever seen.

"That can't be! Professor Quirrell was a great man and a great professor. All of his students loved him and would have used his lessons to effectively fight against Voldemort. I'm sorry, but you must have been lied to."

"Perhaps. I advise you stay wary of Hermione."

"I already am."

"And tell me anything odd you notice about her; I might help you make sense of it. Anything unusual yet, besides the resurrection and the aura of purity?"

"Well... she knows a very advanced spell that Harry Potter invented, and she's the only person besides him who can cast it. A Super Patronus, that takes the form of a human, and can destroy Dementors."

"Destroy Dementors? Bless Harry Potter; the Interdict has failed to quash magic. We're advancing as fast as the Muggles again. I hope he manages to teach his spell to more than one person. Have you considered asking him to teach it to you?"

"I'd very much like that, but I don't have the courage to ask."

"I know you don't think very highly of Gryffindor, but you need to build up that courage, or you're never going to get anything in life. You only have so many years ahead of you on this Earth. Anything else interesting about Miss Granger?"

"She's taken to keeping a phoenix."

"That would be very reassuring. Lord Voldemort would never be able to own a phoenix as I understand it; they're some of the most objective measures of morality in existence. Have you seen it?"

"No..."

"Oh. You should ask her to show it to you; if she refuses, increase your caution tenfold."

"Alright. That sounds reasonable. I very much doubt that she's faking it, though. A lot of the Ravenclaw girls say she's showed it to them in their Common Room."

"That sounds fairly watertight, though I can think of at least one way Voldemort could falsify such testimony. I don't trust Ravenclaws, anyway. At least the craftiness of Slytherins is well-known."

"If you don't trust Ravenclaws, how can I possibly expect you to give me good advice about Harry Potter?"

"My advice on that matter is exceedingly simple: speak to him honestly about your faith. If I understand his character correctly, he'll have a reasoned discussion with you, and you will either convince him of the truth, sooner or later, or you will learn that he is fated to be an obstacle to you. It is in your interest to learn quickly which it will be, particularly if you truly are the Third Seventh Son." Ginny considered responding that this sounded like a good course of action, but she had a more pressing thought:

"You know about that?"

"Yes. It was one of the first things I learned about you. Draco told me of your escapade with the door, and after that it was simple deduction. I know the Weasleys by reputation, and it was not difficult to determine how many older brothers you had. Once I figured it out, I knew I had to meet the prophesied hero, the one who will rebuild the church." Ginny's eyes stopped on the phrase "prophesied hero". She was one, wasn't she? What an odd thought, considering she would be more likely to associate that title with Harry.

"Thank you." wrote Ginny, though something didn't seem quite right to her, something she hadn't yet put her finger on.

"I'd like to make clear that I'm a very secret diary, and your secrets are as safe with me as mine are with you." This was meant to be reassuring, but in Ginny's current state of mind, it read as a threat. Tim said he had wanted to meet Ginny. Had Draco really given Ginny the diary of his own free will, or had it convinced him to? What agenda did Tim have? Was he intelligent enough to manipulate anybody into doing anything, using only writing? Could he be trusted about anything he said? Ginny was getting nauseous; her father had once told her not to speak to anything whose brain she couldn't see, and she'd thought it rather stupid advice, but she was beginning to see his point.

"It's been fascinating talking to you, Tim, but I have something I need to do now."

"Thank you. I look forward to our next conversation." Ginny never read this final message, for she had already closed the book and precommitted not to open it again until she had a strategy prepared to ensure she was not being used in some dark scheme.

Chapter 15: Blackmail in Game Theory, Aftermath

Aftermath, Lesath Lestrange:

Lesath tapped his foot nervously, and waited for the staircase to the Headmistress's office to present itself to him. A disgusted-looking Professor Slughorn had instructed him to report to the Headmistress at once. People looked disgusted at him all the time, but given the context, Lesath's heart was pounding, and his mind was racing through every bad thing he had ever done, wondering which one he would be expelled for – or if perhaps he was overestimating the severity of the situation, and he would simply be suspended or killed. The staircase turned to face him, and he ascended to meet his fate. First she spoke something inaudible into her desk, and then she turned to confront Lesath directly.

"Mr. Lestrange?" said the Headmistress. "Please sit down." She sounded calm and sympathetic, and not in the fake-calm manner of someone planning to expel, suspend, or kill you. So Lesath sat down, and kept an open mind, and barely even wondered what was going on. "I am afraid that this conversation will not be pleasant, but given the wider circumstances occurring at the school, that is frankly a relief."

"What is it," muttered Lesath; he was still fairly certain he was in trouble.

"You have turned out to be our first false alarm," said the Headmistress, "and quite an alarm, too. Your case has demonstrated a rather severe flaw in my initial plan, which is that, while children are certainly not to be ignored, immaturity is considered a character flaw for a reason. You see..." She paused, and considered how to relate the recent events to him. "After I announced to the school that, to find the 'Heir of Slytherin', anything suspicious should be reported without question, I was immediately inundated with reports about you. Nearly all of them from girls, most all of them from younger Slytherin girls."

"Who?" said Lesath. He was trying and failing to hide his anger.

"For the sake of obvious privacy concerns, I am not at liberty to say," said the Headmistress. "Now, of course I followed up on these reports, asking for specifics on what about you they considered suspicious. A few of them lied, providing half-baked and easily falsified stories designed to incriminate you as the Heir; they will be disciplined for malicious abuse of Hogwarts resources. But most of them simply described your general behavior and demeanor as of late. They did not seem to understand that your behavior is suggestive not of a secret Dark Lord, but of an awkward teenage boy who is out-of-touch with social norms and standards. In short, the system I created zeroed in on you not because you were a reasonable suspect, but because you were unpopular." Lesath looked back and forth, deep in thought, and the Headmistress stopped because she could see that he needed to process this, though she was at a natural stopping point anyway.

"So why are you telling me all of this?" said Lesath.

"Because," said the Headmistress, starting slowly, "though your accusers did not choose the correct venue to put forward their concerns, we are still glad to have found out, because Hogwarts does not tolerate inappropriate or boundary-violating behavior, particularly of a sexual nature. This is your first warning. If the behavior continues, you will be given detention, and ultimately will face criminal charges, suspension, or even expulsion if it goes further. Is this understood?"

"Yes," said Lesath.

"If you feel you need to learn more about social boundaries and norms, I could direct you to a professional-"

"No," said Lesath, and the Headmistress frowned.

"I advise that you don't bother anyone anytime soon," said the Headmistress. "Now, go. Off. It's bad enough dealing with the Heir of Slytherin and Slytherin's Monster without awkward teenage boys too." She halfheartedly smiled, and Lesath did, too, and left. Girls were so weird. Perhaps he wouldn't find romance until after graduation.

What long years those would be.

Aftermath, Draco Malfoy:

"Hello, Harry," said Draco.

"Hello, Draco," said Harry. He seemed oddly uncomfortable to be talking to Draco. First, Harry apparently hadn't been very well-trained in the Slytherin arts, if he was this bad at hiding his discomfort. Second, his discomfort was very disconcerting. Draco thought he had chose to stop talking to Harry, not the other way around.

"I've wanted to talk to you, about... what's been going on," said Draco. "Do you have time now, or are you busy?" Harry groaned, and instinctively reached for his pocket.

"I always have time," said Harry, and they found a quiet space with a bench. Harry cast as many anti-eavesdropping spells as he considered appropriate.

"Good," said Draco. "We haven't talked in quite some time. How have you been? What have you been up to?"

"I've been fine," said Harry, "and I've mostly been up to official business I'm afraid I can't tell you, or nearly any of my classmates, about."

"Of course," said Draco, concealing his irritation entirely. "Do you have any more idea than the rest of us what's going on, who's causing trouble?"

"Perhaps a bit, but not much," said Harry. "If we'd caught the perpetrator, they would already be publicly known and behind bars. The only alternate case I can see is if we'd caught them but they'd escaped, in which case their identity and that we'd caught them would still be publicly known. The problem is that we don't even have a testable hypothesis, Draco. We don't even have any suspects. We had a couple of suspects at first, but they were very quickly cleared." Draco frowned.

"You're a Parselmouth, Potter," said Draco.

"Yes, I know," said Harry. "That's why I was one of the initial suspects. But I can't be the person doing this, Draco. I have no interest whatsoever in breaking the Line of Merlin Unbroken or the Interdict of Merlin. In fact, there are reasons I can't tell you about that I believe breaking either of those would be a very bad thing."

"I don't mean to cast aspersions on you," said Draco, "but couldn't that simply mean that you're the perpetrator and you're playing one level higher? Trying to drum up pro-Interdict sentiment, to protect it?" Harry swallowed.

"No one's thought of that as far as I know," said Harry. "I'd barely even considered that. It's technically plausible, but there are Muggles who believe in such plans, they're known as 'false flag operations', and the Muggles who are most inclined to believe that they've happened are generally extremely cognitively deficient, but I can't think of any particular reason that couldn't be what happened here. It couldn't have been me, though; as far as I know, there is no nearby risk of the Line of Merlin Unbroken breaking. It's just not something that could be done. Whoever is causing all of this trouble is misinformed about how the Line works, either because they're demanding we destroy it, which is impossible, or because they're trying to protect it from being destroyed, which is also impossible."

"Hmm," said Draco. "Whoever did this is still definitely a Parselmouth. Do you know any other Parselmouths around the school? Parselmouths are supposed to know each other."

"I was only aware of one other Parselmouth at the school," said Harry, "and she was also one of the initial suspects."

"No, Granger-" started Draco. Harry smiled. "It is Granger, isn't it?"

"You are very perceptive, Draco," said Harry. "Don't let her know you know, though; she would kill me."

"Of course," said Draco.

"And she was aware of one other Parselmouth at the school," said Harry, "who to the best of my knowledge was investigated and cleared when it was determined he didn't even know he was a Parselmouth before."

"So there's a secret Parselmouth at school," said Draco. "Either a student or a teacher. Lockhart-"

"Maybe," said Harry. "I have an alternate theory, though. Voldemort was a Parselmouth, you know."

"No..." said Draco, not because he didn't know, but because he could already tell that Potter was leading into some deeper horrifying revelation.

"Voldemort might not be completely dead," said Harry. "I believe, based on evidence, that he has objects lying around in random places, by which he might possess someone – a teacher or student at Hogwarts, for example. And then, theoretically, he could speak in Parseltongue, and open the Chamber." Draco stared into space for something like twenty seconds, with the most appalled look on his face. "What? What is it?"

"I think I might have-" Draco's voice went out, and Harry shot up out of his seat.

"What happened?" asked Harry, with much more force, and he directed Draco to stand up and walk with him – and quickly, too.

"IhadamysteriousobjectlefttomebymyfatherthatcouldwriteandthinklikeahumananditconvincedmetogiveittoanotherHogwartsstudentGinnyWeasleyandohmyGodisshegoingtobeokay?" said Draco, keeping up with Harry.

"Follow me," said Harry.

"Are we going to find Ginny, and save her?" said Draco.

"Probably," said Harry, "but we're talking to the Headmistress first. I want you to tell her everything you know."

"Okay," said Draco, "but what if the Headmistress can't do anything?"

"Then we won't be able to do anything either," said Harry.

"Will we be able to save her?" said Draco. "Will she be punished?"

"Assuming that your suggested explanation is the correct one," said Harry, "which seems like the Occam's Razor solution at the moment, then we will almost certainly be able to save her, and she will almost certainly not be punished. Nobody is held accountable for things they do while they're possessed. Like-" Harry stopped himself from saying something, and Draco wondered what it could possibly be. Here was the entrance to the Headmistress's room. Harry approached the password-receiving gargoyle, but was interrupted by-

"Harry! Draco!" said Professor Lockhart. "What are you doing here?"

"No time, Professor," said Harry, and he whispered something Draco somehow managed not to hear at all. Absolutely nothing happened, and Harry repeated whatever he'd just said. "Why isn't it working?"

"The Headmistress is in a particularly private meeting with a student," said Professor Lockhart, "and I advise that you return in ten minutes."

"But this is more important!" said Harry. "This is an emergency!" A suspicion was beginning to sneak up on Draco, and Professor Lockhart raised an eyebrow.

"Really?" said the Professor. "What kind of emergency?"

Aftermath, Cho Chang:

"There is a fountain filled with blood, drawn from Immanuel's veins, and sinners plunge beneath that flood, lose all their guilty stains."

As Cedric's body was lowered into the cold and lonely ground, Cho Chang failed to hear the words of the hymn being sung. It was just as well; she was not an adherent of the religion in which the words had significance. Nor, for that matter, was the majority of the choir singing it. It was just a tradition, a funeral tradition, an ancient thing that goes unquestioned and largely unseen, a specific type of prior that can be particularly difficult to root out. It was simply how the funeral was supposed to be.

But this funeral was not supposed to be at all. It wasn't supposed to go like this. Cho Chang was supposed to become a widow – or create a widower – around age 200. She wasn't supposed to be mourning the love of her life at 13. Of course, Cedric wasn't truly the love of Cho's life – apparently. Because she would live much, much longer. Wouldn't she? Actually, with the advent of the Peverell Family Hospital, she never had to die at all. …Cedric had never had to die at all. They could have truly been together forever, exploring the stars in some magic craft of Harry's. Why had that been ripped away from her? Why had Cedric been ripped away from everybody? Cho tried to feel hatred or anger at whoever had done this, but she was not capable; her grief was too overwhelming of an emotion.

"When he laughed, you swore you'd never cry again," Cho had told a reporter, through tears, before the funeral had begun. But Cho didn't want to talk to anyone, least of all the press. She just wanted to think, but that was too hard; depression releases chemicals in the brain that inhibit regular thinking. So she just wanted to take in the world around her, and judge it. Nobody else at the funeral looked nearly sad enough. They all looked sad, just not enough. It was as if they had all gotten so used to carrying out funerals that they were simply playing a role, and it had slipped their minds how genuinely awful it all was, particularly now, now that we were all so close to the finish line that the Philosopher's Stone represented.

The Malfoys were sitting next to the Weasleys. The Malfoys were sitting next to the Weasleys. The Malfoys didn't even seem bothered by that. Had Cedric's death truly shaken everybody up that much? That made Cho feel ever so infinitesimally better. Draco Malfoy had lost his father last year, hadn't he? Cho supposed she would find no shortage at Hogwarts of people who had experienced death. She still felt particularly alone.

It occurred to Cho that with the advent of the Philosopher's Stone, there was absolutely no reason that anything like this should ever happen again. Accidents and murders? If anything short of immediately or quickly lethal damage could be recovered, why wouldn't you minimize risk as much as possible? There was no reason whatsoever that this couldn't or shouldn't be Cho's last funeral. There was no reason whatsoever that this couldn't or shouldn't be the last funeral in the world.

Cho had not been able to cast her Patronus, not since she had learned of Cedric's death in certain terms. She was still recovering from her mental reeling, and would not return to Hogwarts until January, still in miserable condition. But it was that thought – the last funeral in the world – that would allow Cho to cast a different Patronus, several years afterwards.

Aftermath, Tom Riddle Prime:

The man who could not even remember his own name drifted through space, amidst Platonic forms and timeless physics. He was and was not a gemstone, and so he could and could not think – like a sleeping man, he was vaguely aware of everything around him, but he could not hold onto any of it. He could not think, and he could not remember; he could not even long for the day he would be free. He could only perceive and dream, like an Elder God that had once been human and would someday be human once more.

"Headmistress," said the boy, who was wearing the man who could not even remember his own name, "I am becoming increasingly certain of one of my first hypotheses, that this is the work of a horcrux of Voldemort."

"I thought he was on your person," said the older woman, and she gestured at the finger that held the man. "And in this state, he could not access his horcruxes."

"He is," said the boy, "and he can't, but he made two types of horcruxes. We have been referring to the more advanced type. He also made a more primitive kind, with entirely different properties." The older woman frowned.

"Properties that you suspect leave them dangerous," said the older woman.

"Yes, absolutely," said the boy. "Because instead of being connected to the main Voldemort, and therefore being vulnerable to attacks on Voldemort's main body that also influence his soul, they contain an entirely independent copy of Voldemort, diverging from the original at the moment that they're created." The older woman grew a look of horror. "The only possible complicating factor, which is completely ambiguous, is that I was under the impression Voldemort had destroyed many, most, or all of them himself, when he moved onto the more advanced sort of horcrux."

"No," said the older woman. "Not Tom Riddle. He always had some sort of backup plan in mind in case we defeated his first intentions."

"Speaking of the original Tom Riddle, though," said the boy, "I'd prefer that we not keep him on my person anymore. Even with all of the extra security measures you've placed on Hermione and me, I feel the risk is too large, particularly if I'm correct that it's another Tom Riddle doing all of this." He removed the gemstone that was the man.

"If not on your person, then where?" asked the older woman, and she visibly panicked and squirmed away. "The Transfiguration must be sustained."

"Yes," said the boy, "but it doesn't need to be sustained by myself. It was foolish to assume it did in the first place; I'm too important to put another egg in my basket like that. It should preferably be sustained by someone trusted off-campus. I'd suggest Moody, but he seems a bit obvious. How about a high-ranking Unspeakable? I can't imagine any Dark Lord catching Bode off-guard..."

Chapter 16: Programming

In Charms class, on the first day that classes resumed, Ginny was distracted. She could afford to; she had a natural talent for Charms. Was it right to pursue Draco and Harry simultaneously? Tim had dismissed the matter as girlish foolishness immediately upon hearing of it, so she had tried to block it out of her mind, to feel more mature. But it was a serious concern. Perhaps almost as serious as the question of whether it was right to pursue either of them. Ginny certainly felt like a girl, and was physically one so far as anyone could tell, but her soul said something different, and it was a routinely-made point, where Ginny came from, that the soul was what truly counted, in the end. The Bible prescribed awful punishments for male homosexuality, though those punishments had been abandoned long ago, and secularism, the most dominant religion in the modern wizarding world, thought it was cruel even to disapprove of the practice. Ginny would hate to wind up in Hell over some dumb misunderstanding about her gender, and even though her view of God's omnibenevolence suggested that that was an absurdity, it was still enough of a looming possibility to concern her.

"Luna," Ginny had said, just before class started. "I have a very personal question to ask you, about something very secret. Can I trust you to keep it between us?" Luna had put a hand just in front of her mouth in a futile attempt to hide that she was smiling more widely than she normally was.

"Um, of course," said Luna. "What is it?"

"Okay, um," said Ginny. "When I got to Hogwarts, I discovered something very surprising and very distressing about myself. Basically, there was a mess with some wards, and then I learned from Madam Pomfrey that my soul says that I'm a boy." Luna had not looked confused at all; it would have been very odd if she had. "But I don't feel like a boy, and I never have. I'm not biologically a boy, or even ambiguous. So, to go forward, just, what am I?"

"Ginny, of course you're a girl," said Luna.

"But why?" said Ginny. "Are you sure?"

"No," said Luna. "You're sure. Because it's in your head. The mind's the final arbiter of this kind of thing, because the body can be changed with magic – especially now, with the Philosopher's Stone, come to think of it – and the soul contains – roughly half a page of text. That's all. It can be wrong." Ginny had frowned, because that was not her understanding of what a soul was at all. "And also, I like you, so I'm pretty sure you're a girl."

"Come again?" said Ginny, and there had been a long pause, as Luna had just been smiling, before a sudden realization. "Oh." Luna had nodded, and Ginny had realized that, given the vast gulf between their worldviews, Luna's opinion didn't mean much to her, except insofar as she was a friend.

The lesson today was of particular interest to Ginny. One of the spells being taught today was a castable form of the Remembrall's magic, which, upon being correctly cast, shot up a number of black sparks proportional to the number of things forgotten by the caster. Ginny consistently produced more sparks with the Charm than anyone else in the class, which at least vaguely concerned her. Luna, conversely, produced the fewest; each time she correctly cast the spell, only a single projectile emanated from her wand.

Ginny was thinking about the nature of Charms, and about her first day at Hogwarts – specifically, the moment when she had been knocked unconscious by some Parseltongue enchantment. She carefully thought about what she remembered of Professor Flitwick's description of the spell, and decided that, as a Parselmouth herself, and a future Charms Master, it was her responsibility to learn it, as she could make better use of it than nearly anyone. So she lingered after class.

"Professor Flitwick," said Ginny. "I'd like to ask a question. There's a spell I'd like to learn, but I want to know if it's feasible for me to learn it at my level, and as far as I know, you're the only one who knows it to teach it to me."

"What spell?" said the Professor.

"I don't know what it's called," said Ginny, "but it's the spell you described to me on the first day, that you used to drown out the secret message on the Sorting Hat – and, I'm assuming, that was used to put the secret message on the Sorting Hat in the first place."

"Hmm," said Professor Flitwick. "That is a surprisingly easy Charm – I'd probably say second year, but you've shown surprising talent. I could easily teach it to you before my next class, but I want to get the approval of the Headmistress first; it wasn't a secret when I found it, just obscure, but that might have changed."

"Alright," said Ginny, and Professor Flitwick showed himself out of the room. Somewhere, Ginny heard the sound of a Patronus being cast. A slight delay, and several Patronuses later...

"Okay," said Professor Flitwick. "I've gotten permission to teach you this spell, but I want it to be very clear that you should inform me on a weekly basis of any novel uses of the spell that you invent. And I fully expect you to invent novel uses of the spell, because you're a Parselmouth, and therefore have access to much more of the spell's potential than I ever did."

"Understood," said Ginny. Professor Flitwick nodded, and displayed his wand; Ginny instinctively reached for her own.

"Now – first the wand movement," said Professor Flitwick. "The physical wand movement is very simple. The thoughts you must focus on simultaneously with the wand movement are more complicated, but still simple in their own way, but I'll get to them next. To cast this spell, you must trace an equilateral triangle in the air. The exact size of the triangle does not matter, as long as each side is equal in length. The bottom side of the triangle should parallel the horizon, assuming that you're standing upright, and the order of the sides should be left, bottom, right. So you start and end at the top point of the triangle." He demonstrated all of this in the air in front of him as he explained. "Is that all very clear?"

"Yes," said Ginny, and she mirrored Professor Flitwick's movements, though not reversed, until she had gotten it right.

"Now, then, for the thoughts," said Professor Flitwick. "While tracing the left side of the triangle, focus on where you want the 'node' generated by the spell to be. Whatever location you choose must be relative to an object. You could choose a portable object, like a ball or a stick, and therefore have a portable node. Or you could choose something fixed, like Hogwarts or the Earth itself, if you want the node to be fixed."

"While tracing the bottom side of the triangle," said Professor Flitwick, "focus on what conditions you want to activate the node. I don't know exactly how versatile this step is. The nodes seem to have some sensory mechanism that they're capable of examining; at least enough that 'the Sorting Hat says Slytherin' can be a condition. I was able to confirm that they don't have access to all human knowledge, only the sensory information immediately surrounding them. Like many idealistic fools, I am eagerly awaiting the invention of a Charm that accidentally grants its user effective omniscience or omnipotence, in the hopes of getting to it first, even though Magical Theorists say it's impossible. So of course I took the time to check if this spell was it."

"While tracing the right side of the triangle, focus on what you want the node to say when activated," said Professor Flitwick. "This is the feature of the Charm I am not able to make full use of, as the nodes only speak in Parseltongue, and you may not even correctly cast this step without being a Parselmouth yourself. I was able to find a workaround, as you know – sorry – but I was fully aware of the potential uses of the spell that I had no access to, which was disheartening. I envy the uses you are sure to find here." Ginny didn't know whether to seem proud or sorry.

"When you have completed the triangle, say the incantation – 'Sapespeck' – and the Charm is complete," said Professor Flitwick. "Several interesting notes about the result – the resulting node is invisible to anyone except for the original caster, who sees it as a bright green dot suspended in space. The node does not consume any of the original caster's magic, or at least not a large enough portion of the original caster's magic that I was able to tell after creating a hundred of them. Judging by Slytherin's node on the Sorting Hat, it continues well after the original caster's death. And it's resistant to magic-canceling spells like 'Finite Incantatem', except, again, from the original caster. All-in-all, it's a very powerful, very versatile Charm. If its use weren't limited to Parseltongue, almost all of Hogwarts would know it."

"Now," said Professor Flitwick, "would you like to try? Affix a node to an object somewhere in this room, and give it a simple condition we can easily check."

"Alright," said Ginny. She was fairly certain she had understood everything Professor Flitwick had said – perhaps she had even understood some things he'd said that he hadn't understood himself. Swish-swish-swish. "Sapespeck." A green dot appeared above Professor Flitwick's desk. Ginny was impressed with herself; even she often took multiple times to get a Charm right, and those were first year Charms. Perhaps being a Parselmouth helped.

"Did it work?" asked Professor Flitwick. Ginny nodded, smiled, put her wand down, and clapped. A hollow voice said:

"Ssalutationss, sschool."

In her first day of usage, Ginny discovered a variety of nuances of the Sapespeck Charm that Professor Flitwick had not happened upon. If you cast the Charm not-quite-right, but close enough for it to tell that you'd tried to cast it, a voice would tell you, in Parseltongue, a rudimentary description of what you had done wrong. You couldn't create two nodes in the same place – if you tried, the Charm would tell you: "You have made a misstake. Sspecks musst occupy different pointss in sspace." You could create them so close together that the green dots that indicated them overlapped, though – in fact, you could even create them so close together that they might as well, for all practical purposes, have been in the same place.

The truth requirements of Parseltongue coming from Sapespeck nodes were slightly looser than the regular truth requirements. The caster needed to either believe that what they were saying was currently true, or that it would probably be true when the node was activated; either was sufficient. Ginny thoroughly tested this, and was able to produce nodes that said false things in Parseltongue – one node, for example, would, upon hearing a clap, say "There iss a coin under me," because it was true when the node was initially created, even though Ginny immediately removed the Knut after casting. If Ginny attempted to produce a node that was true in neither sense – neither when it was created nor in the probable event that it was activated – then she would receive only a "You have made a misstake. Invalid ssnake wordss."

The nodes were not much smarter than you would expect from a Charm. On one occasion, Ginny tried to make a node that would hiss words of encouragement at Slytherins when they passed, and she simply received a "You have made a misstake. Invalid conditionss." She was still able to achieve her goal, though, by changing her mental wording to "when you see robes with green trim". The only other notable limitation she encountered was that she could not affix nodes to her own wand – the response to that was "You have made a misstake. Sspecks may only be removed by casster, and musst be able to be removed."

Ginny had one idea that she was particularly excited to show Harry Potter. She barely completed it in time for their date.

"Harry, you have to look at this," said Ginny, and she held up a piece of paper.

"It's blank," said Harry.

"Yes," said Ginny. "But I've enchanted it. Say an addition problem."

"I thought we were here to discuss your Wizard Christianity," said Harry.

"We can get to that next," said Ginny. "I thought you'd think this was neat."

"Two plus four," said Harry, shrugging.

"Ssixx," said the paper, after a quick bout of inaudible hissing of code words.

"Impressive," said Harry.

"Do something harder," said Ginny.

"Two plus one half," said Harry.

"Three," said the paper.

"What?" said Ginny. "No, like-"

"Five plus six point four," said Harry.

"Eleven," said the paper.

"I plus I," said Harry. The paper didn't respond.

"Three plus three plus three," said Harry.

"Sseven. Ssix," said the paper.

"No, I mean bigger numbers," said Ginny.

"Oh," said Harry, disappointed. "Five hundred and ninety three plus three hundred and ninety four."

"Nine hundred and eighty sseven," said the paper.

"Very impressive," said Harry, though that certainly wasn't what his face said. "How did you enchant this to speak in Parseltongue?"

"There's a Charm I could teach you," said Ginny. "Professor Flitwick taught it to me, although he couldn't make full use of it-"

"Because he's not a Parseltongue, of course," said Harry.

"Parselmouth," said Ginny.

"It's that spell," said Harry. "Got it. So we were going to discuss Wizard Christianity, right? Have you ever heard of a place called the Department of Mysteries?"

"Yes," said Ginny.

"I've been there," said Harry. "I could arrange to take you there if you don't believe me, although I'd prefer not to; it's an awfully large hassle with a lot of paperwork involved, and it shouldn't be necessary, I mean, you trust me, right?"
"Yes," said Ginny, though she was subconsciously beginning to have her doubts.

"In the Department of Mysteries, there's a room called the Time Room," said Harry. "Some relatively new and incredibly useful magics have been invented there. In the Time Room, there's a spatial-temporal anomaly called the Well of Time. The Well of Time is an apparently perfectly cylindrical pit, with a sort of spiral pattern on the walls. Every full rotation of the spiral – roughly every meter and a half – is equivalent to one year. Every year, the Well of Time grows one year deeper. It serves as a sort of time viewer – if you press your face up against the side, you receive a vision of something that's already happened; the only reason it can't be used as a spying device is because the visions can't be aimed in space – although they tend to be heavily clustered around the land surface of the Earth – but they can be aimed in time."

"I'm aware of the Well of Time, Harry," said Ginny, and she was smiling. She hadn't expected the conversation to start this way.

"And you're aware of its depth?" said Harry.

"At least a million years deep with no end in sight," said Ginny.

"Actually, the exact depth was recently calculated," said Harry, "because it was determined that the Well of Time is actually conic, allowing its exact size to be determined with very fine instruments. It's 4.57 billion years, exactly in line with the Muggle estimates of the age of the Earth." He stopped, and realized he had gotten sidetracked. "But what do you think the Well of Time is, Ginny?"

"Exactly what you think it is," said Ginny.

"Not a portal to Hell?" said Harry. He frowned.

"No," said Ginny, "not a portal to Hell. The Weasleys haven't been that deluded since Septimus two generations ago. The Earth isn't six thousand years old, Harry, and I'm completely aware of that. I'm aware of the Muggle evidence as well as the magical."

"And you are still a Wizard Christian?" said Harry. Ginny nodded. "Ugh. That kind of rationalization is common in the Muggle world, too."

"I think your mistake is probably that you're fighting the hypothesis that the Bible is the perfect word of God," said Ginny, "which, to be fair, is a hypothesis that a lot of people hold. But it's not a very strong hypothesis to attack. You can break a hypothesis like that by pointing out internal contradictions. Although, let's be honest, here; most people who believe in that hypothesis aren't going to be big on rationalism anyway."

"What do you believe?" said Harry. It was too early for an "and why do you believe it?".

"I believe that the Bible is a historical document," said Ginny, "no, actually, a collection of disparate historical documents, that records events that shine light on the existence and nature of God. Their reliability and value varies considerably; the earliest books are essentially tribal myths, though there might be some truth in them as well."

"So you consider the New Testament more relevant to your beliefs than the Old Testament, then?" said Harry.

"Yes," said Ginny, because it was true, although she hadn't explicitly said it yet, so she was a touch surprised.

"There's only one wizard or witch known to have returned from death without the use of inherently evil magic," said Harry. "And she currently attends this school."

"You are forgetting about Jesus Christ," said Ginny, "who is no ordinary wizard."

"Oh, was he a double witch, then?" said Harry.

"He is the Son of God," said Ginny.

"According to?" said Harry.

"The Bible! Himself! Prophecy!" said Ginny.

"Hmm, prophecy..." said Harry. "Unfortunately, I can't check whether it was delivered by a legitimate Seer; the Hall of Prophecy has been destroyed."

"This all happened long before-" started Ginny. "Wait, it has?"

"Never mind," said Harry. "Anyway, I have it on good authority that Hermione Granger was never truly medically dead; she was only dead in a limited, magical sense. You can't actually survive actual dying without extremely evil magic, which you need to arrange in advance of the death. It's impossible. I suppose you're going to say that's the point, and it's a miracle."

"It is indeed the point," said Ginny. "A major theme of what the Bible records is miracles."

"There's no such thing," said Harry. "Have you ever seen a miracle? Do you really believe that they happen, or do you only believe that you believe that they happen? Does this world look like a world that has miracles in it to you, or does it look like one that operates on consistent rules?"

"What's the Well of Time?" said Ginny. Harry considered the purpose of the question before deciding how to answer it.

"It's either a magical invention or a naturally occurring magical phenomena," said Harry. "I'm not sure which, although I suspect that all magic is constructed somehow or another, in the distant past." Ginny smiled.

"You referred to it as an anomaly, and that sounds about right to me," said Ginny. "Consider other possible terms for 'anomaly', though. A Muggle might just say 'magic', because they don't know that that's something normal and understood. Someone like me might call it a 'miracle'."

"Ginny, it's all magic," said Harry. "It's all understandable, the question is just whether or not we understand it already. This is the Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, not the Hogwarts School of Prayer and Miracles. There aren't any real miracles."

"Oh, well I'm glad we understand everything, then," said Ginny. "I guess the Department of Mysteries can just shut down, then. Since there isn't anything mysterious to study."

"Ginny, you can't put everything you don't understand yet in a box called 'God' or 'miracles' and call it a day," said Harry. "That's a God-of-the-gaps argument, and it should be clear why it's broken thinking."

"I'm not saying it's not understandable," said Ginny. "I'm saying that anomalies happen, and are important and interesting."

"Have you ever heard of theodicy, Ginny?" asked Harry. He had just researched the matter over the previous week.

"That's the set of omniscience, omnipotence, omnibenevolence, right?" said Ginny. "I've heard of it and believe in it, although omniscience is awfully redundant with omnipotence, isn't it? I think omnipresence would be a better third quality."

"No," said Harry. "Theodicy is the question of how, given omniscience, omnipotence, and omnibenevolence, how does suffering happen, particularly suffering that could widely be agreed on as unjust."

"Oh," said Ginny, "the problem of evil."

"Yes," said Harry. "How do you resolve theodicy, Ginny?"

"Well, first off, to truly prevent humans from being evil would strip them of all agency," said Ginny.

"The free will argument," said Harry. "Classic. But not all suffering even results from evil. That's why the problem of evil is really just a more mainstream form of theodicy."

"Well, secondly," said Ginny, "I don't believe that any suffering is of real significance, because an omnibenevolent God would permit us all to live forever." Harry was clearly restraining himself from something.

"Do you believe in Hell, Ginny?" asked Harry.

"Maybe?" said Ginny. "Probably not? My family told me about it as if it were real, but they didn't seem to really believe in it, as if they were quoting a fairy tale about Father Christmas at me. And my gut tells me that it contradicts omnibenevolence, hard, and omnibenevolence is a much more important belief."

"Oh, look at my wrist, I've got to go," said Harry, immediately rising and heading for the door. "There's an appointment I forgot."

The next Friday, Ginny learned that, "to shake things up", Blaise Zabini was the new Vice President of the More Sane Squad.

Chapter 18: Mysteries, Pt 1

After a week-long intermission, the story resumes! The trigger warning at the beginning of chapter one has, on further consideration, been updated.

9.03 ATLANTIS

9.04 BUREAUCRACY

9.05 CHANCE

9.06 DEATH

9.00 EGRESS

9.07 FORCE

9.02 HUB

9.08 MINDS

9.09 OCEANS

9.10 PROPHECY (decommissioned, pending replacement)

9.11 LOVE

9.12 REALITY

9.13 SPACE

9.14 TIME

9.15 WORLDS

9.01 ZERO

Zacharias Smith was revived shortly after the attack. The good news was that no further students were petrified for the remainder of the term, or during the winter holidays. The bad news was that interviews with Zacharias revealed no new information that could lead to Cedric, Justin, and Ernie's killer being apprehended. The worse news was that, against the express wishes of the Hogwarts administration, rumors circulated that St. Mungo's had neglected to manufacture more than one Potion of Reanimation. They were very expensive to brew, which explained their being in short supply, but they were also very time-consuming to brew, which allowed even curable petrification to be a greater threat than it would be, had the healers bothered to keep a large reserve supply.

Just one day later, Luna Lovegood – who was wearing gloves herself, coated in Diricawl feathers – returned the diary to Ginevra Weasley, whilst smiling.

"So what have you figured out?" said Ginny.

"I owled it to my dad," said Luna. "And he sent it back with this letter, which explains what it is and how to take care of it. I'll give it to you so you can find out what it is and how to take care of it."

"Thank you," said Ginny, and she accepted the parchment, though of course she wouldn't read it. The Lovegoods were insane, especially in matters like this, and Xenophilius was the reason why.

"I'll just sum up the major points," said Luna. "It's called a horcrux; it contains a soul fragment of a human being and only a very advanced dark wizard can make one."

"Sure, Luna," said Ginny.

"It's very difficult to destroy," said Luna. "I included a list of things you can use to destroy it if the need arises, although I don't think you personally have access to any of them. Oh, and it can possess people. Normally a horcrux can possess people with impunity, as long as they touch it, but this one's been specially enchanted not to possess anyone who hasn't consented. Dad says he hasn't seen anything like it. Of course I haven't consented to be possessed, but I'm still wearing these gloves just to be safe." Ginny glanced at Luna's hands, saw no gloves, and took a step back. "That's why you're wearing gloves, too, right?"

"Uh huh," said Ginny.

"But you didn't consent to be possessed either," said Luna.

"What, no, what are you talking about?" said Ginny.

"Ginny Weasley, I swear to Wizard God if you wind up as some Dark Lord's possessed stooge because you signed your brain away like an idiot, I will hang you from the rafters," said Luna, and then she clapped her hands over her mouth. "I didn't mean – I'm sorry -"

"No, Luna, it's fine," said Ginny. "You're right to be concerned. This is serious business. But I haven't signed my life away. I know to be conscientious. You've helped me to see that more than anyone."

"Okay," said Luna; she particularly perked up at this last sentiment. "I just - I mean, I thought it was probably some kind of serious risk. He tried to get me to agree to possession, and I barely managed to distract him by talking about unimportant things like Divination and what a creep Lesath is."

"Alright," said Ginny. "I'll keep everything you've told me in mind. Goodbye!"

Ginny later found out from Tim that Luna had been particularly unhelpful, paranoid, and unpleasant to talk to, and was not a true Seer. Ginny felt sorry for Luna, but couldn't argue with any of Tim's points. She soon began making progress with her Sapespeck computing, through a combination of Muggle maths textbooks, some programming help from Colin (who she still managed to keep out of the loop), and her own personal discovery of Sapespeck Maxima, a Charm that made editing large Sapespeck systems easier.

By the time classes resumed in January, she had constructed a more advanced calculator capable of adding - as well as subtracting - any indefinitely long sequence of numbers. It could parse negative numbers as well as decimals; she had held off on supporting fractions until she had a better grasp on what division was, though she had added case-by-case patches for phrases like "and a half", "and a quarter", and so on, which were interpreted, for example, as "point five", "point two five", and so on. Coming down the pipeline, though, on a different sheet of paper, was limited support for multiplication. Ginny could feel the features creeping along like Eclipse Ivy, and she loved it. If she could make an inanimate object smarter than herself, then she would.

Just before the spring term began, a notice went out to all students that Professor Lockhart was running a Patronus workshop, targeted primarily at first years, but also accepting older students who had either failed or not attempted to cast a Patronus the previous year. Participating, however, required a parent's signature on a permission slip, as the workshop would be held in the Department of Mysteries. This was not difficult for Ginny to obtain.

"Frankly, it's safer than Hogwarts," said Arthur, as he signed. "I've been to the Department of Mysteries before; they were showing me Grabthar's Hammer in the Force Room. They thought they were on the verge of reverse-engineering it and they thought it might be possible to construct more of them without even using magic, so they were investigating the possibility that Muggles might figure it out. I think it's further off than they seemed to think – but anyway, my point is, you'll be herded around by Unspeakables at all time; you'll only go where you're supposed to. There are dangerous things in the Department of Mysteries, but you wouldn't be able to get anywhere near them even if you wanted to."

The fact that no students were petrified during the Christmas break seemed to Ginny to be weak evidence that the culprit was someone who, like her, had chosen to go home during the holidays. The administration did not even take it that way, though; it would be too easy for the attacker to put off their crimes a month to push investigations away from themselves. In any case, Ginny had more important things on her mind – how could she live with herself if she wound up with a standard old Patronus while Harry and Hermione remained the only two people in the world with upgraded human Patronuses?

"Well, Ginny, a Patronus is a journey of personal discovery and self-actualization," said Harry.

"Don't you give me that, Harry Potter," said Ginny. "That's not how you talk. You're hiding something. How do I get a human Patronus?"

"It's complicated and dangerous to teach," said Harry. "Even just giving you a bad hint could lead to your being permanently unable to cast any kind of Patronus."

"You taught her," said Ginny.

"I can't just teach anyone," said Harry. Ginny pouted, and Harry got the look on his face that he always did when he was beginning an experiment. "Well, though... I'll give you one hint. But don't be too disappointed if you wind up with a regular old animal Patronus. It's still better than nothing, if you wind up in a combat situation where a Patronus is needed or if you need to contact someone or confirm that they're alive. And don't tell anyone the hint, or even that I gave you one. I don't want to be mobbed by more requests like this."

"What's the hint?" said Ginny, although she would really rather be able to cast nothing at all than be able to cast an animal Patronus only. People who couldn't cast Patronuses were at least dark and deep and brooding.

"A regular animal Patronus is powered by a happy memory of the past," said Harry. "The True Patronus, the Patronus Two Point Oh, is powered by a happy plan for the future."

"Okay, got it," said Ginny, and she smiled. Harry seemed disappointed in her nonchalant approach to hearing this wisdom, and left.

Ginny sucked in her breath. She'd largely avoided Hermione, out of some kind of uncontrollable, irrational hatred. It was a source of some regret for her, and in retrospect had feelings had spiraled beyond anything reasonable, but nonetheless, she would definitely make an exception to her "steer-clear-of-Hermione" policy now. She had something practical to accomplish.

"Hi, Hermione," said Ginny.

"Ginny Weasley?" said Hermione. "Hello, I haven't seen much of you!"

"Is that so," muttered Ginny, and Hermione nearly left for the Ravenclaw table, because it wasn't completely clear that she still had something to say. "There's something Harry asked me to ask you."

"Oh?" said Hermione.

"I asked Harry how to make a Patronus like his, and he gave me – me exclusively, that is – a hint, and he told me to ask you for another one," said Ginny.

"Is that so?" said Hermione, and Ginny nodded. "Hmm... Dementors are a riddle, and the upgraded Patronus is the answer. Or is that the hint he already gave you?" Ginny nodded; if she was going to lie to get extra hints, she might as well get three instead of two. "Alright, then... Harry's Patronus was directly tied to my resurrection." Ginny was barely able to prevent her mouth from hanging open. "I hope that was helpful! Goodbye!"

How on Earth could Ginny even hope to compete with a girl Harry had literally brought back from the brink of death with a historic spell of his own invention?

"Wait! Hermione!" said Ginny.

"What?" said Hermione.

"What are your views on the existence of an afterlife?" asked Ginny.

"Of course not," said Hermione, immediately flustered. "I mean, you're not trying to weasel more hints out of me? Are you?"

"No," said Ginny. "I've just been thinking about it lately."

"Oh," said Hermione. "Harry told me about you. Between you and me, I think you can believe whatever you want, but, personally, I don't believe in that. For a brief while, my faith in that actually shot up after I, y'know, came back to life, but Harry broke the illusion for me. He had to. Visions that can be interpreted as an afterlife are reasonably common in people who have near-death experiences, but it's a purely neurochemical phenomenon, not supernatural at all."

"Oh," said Ginny. A single sub-belief point of evidence for a deeply-held belief will not invalidate that belief if it is itself invalidated. Do not allow that fear to prevent you from updating your beliefs, or even allow it to make you more skeptical of facts that broadly suggest that your deeply-held beliefs are wrong.

"And anyway, no, that's not for me," said Hermione. "I haven't seen a good debate about it, ever, but I do know what my position is. I think Harry is being monstrously unfair to you, by the way; if you feel the same, then feel free to talk to me about it. Is there anything else you want to talk about now? I really do need to get to the Ravenclaw Table, or they'll wonder where I am and my food will get cold."

"Um, no," said Ginny. "Goodbye."

"Goodbye," said Hermione, and she left. Ginny considered the fact that Hermione was not much like she had imagined her to be, but she did not reflect on it.

The True Patronus is powered not by a memory but by a plan.

It is the answer to the riddle of the Dementor.

It pertains to resurrection.

Ginny repeated these three things in her head, over and over, for an entire day. She repeated them to herself as she slept, and she repeated them to herself as she stepped in a single file line consisting of most of her class and a few older students, through a fireplace, to the Ministry of Magic. Gilderoy Lockhart was waiting for her on the other side, and once his role call was complete, he guided his young students as a group through the main lobby, past a checkpoint, and to the Ministry's elevator, which had dozens of seats and moved forwards and backwards and left and right just as much as it moved up and down.

"LEVEL NINE, DEPARTMENT OF MYSTERIES," read a calm, cool, and distinctly unsettling voice, when they had reached their final destination. The only conclusion Ginny had thus far gathered from her hints was that Dementors were a manifestation of an abstract concept, and that the True Patronus was somehow powered by your approach to solving the non-magical form of that abstract concept. It was known to happen that magical creatures would originate as manifestations of abstract concepts; phoenixes, for example, were representations of a promise of eternity. For this reason, depictions of them were common decorations in churches and on wedding invitations.

"Hello, Lockhart," said one Unspeakable, who appeared to distinctly distrust the Defense Professor.

"Hello, Croaker," said Professor Lockhart.

"You're here for the Dementor exercise, correct?" said Unspeakable Croaker.

"Indeed," said Lockhart, and his smile just wouldn't stop.

"You have delivered the lecture on the properties of Dementors, and on how to produce a normal Patronus?" said Croaker.

"Of course," said Lockhart, and he nodded broadly.

"Follow me," said Croaker, to the entire group from Hogwarts, and he led them into the Department of Mysteries proper, which Ginny's father had described to her.

It was a large circular room, with eleven featureless doors, twelve if you counted the one the class had just walked through, evenly spaced around the room's circumference. Each of the doors had an Unspeakable standing in front of it, wand drawn; they took shifts so that each door was guarded at all times. It simply wouldn't do if someone could sneak in after hours. There was a large circle drawn on the floor, just short of the edge of the room.

"Is that Amortentia?" said a Gryffindor named Romilda Vane, and she pointed at a door that had a strong magical aura emanating from it.

"Yes," said Professor Lockhart, quietly. "An entire fountain of it." Romilda stood in awe. Something about the magical signature didn't seem right to Ginny. She supposed she didn't know how the magical signature compounded in such a large quantity. But come to think of it, how had they gotten such a large quantity? Amortentia took serious sacrifice to create; how many wizards had lost their magic and their wands to power the Love Room? The Love Room was the one where they would keep Amortentia, right?

"We cannot confirm or deny that at this time," said the Unspeakable in front of the Love Room, who was wearing completely opaque black glasses.

"Everyone stand inside the red circle," said Unspeakable Croaker. "As close to the center of the room as possible." Ginny looked down, and saw that they were all well within it; Unspeakable Croaker closed the door to the outside world, and immediately, all of the Unspeakables in the room disappeared, along with the doors they were guarding. A few seconds later, they reappeared, but they were all scrambled; their positions and their order were completely different.

"Dementors this way," said one Unspeakable, who sent up sparks to attract the students' attention, and the door behind him opened a crack. The crowd made its way over to the Unspeakable, whose head was obscured by a cloud of smoke that didn't seem to leave his head, and stepped through the door into the Death Room.

"Jeepers!" said Colin, pointing at the enormous triangular stone structure at the bottom of the chamber's chasm. "Is that the Veil?" A black surface rippled and fluttered between the two lines.

"Yes, absolutely," said Professor Lockhart.

"We cannot confirm or deny that at this time," said the Unspeakable, and he guided them away from the chasm towards a more nondescript corridor, which was very long and was also made of stone, though it was less arcane than the Veil chamber. It led to a smaller, even less arcane room that had wood trim and pleasant lighting. There was a heavy stone door that the Unspeakable glanced at expectantly. "Behind this door is a pit containing all known Dementor specimens remaining after the purge of Azkaban."

"How do you keep Nundus from forming?" interrupted Colin, who was roundly shushed.

"There are not nearly enough Dementors present for the formation of a Nundu," said the Unspeakable. "And even if there were, we are not planning to perform an execution here any time soon, or ever. As I was saying, a pair of Unspeakables will escort a Dementor to this room momentarily, and you will take turns to face it one-on-one. Everyone who isn't currently facing the Dementor will wait in the hall."

"A Dementor's Kiss is required to initiate Nundu formation," explained Professor Lockhart, to Colin, during a lull. Soon thereafter, the room was evacuated of all except Karissa, who was going first. Ginny could feel the Dementor's presence, even though she was not looking at it. It was a distinctly wrong feeling, exactly what she expected, but real. It told her intuitively to flee better than any Boggart could, but she knew she would face it and overcome it. What could it possibly represent? Soon Ginny heard Karissa shout something, and there was a glow opposite the Dementor's, and Karissa returned triumphant.

Some weren't so lucky. The group was about evenly split between those able and those unable to produce Patronuses, though it was invariably found that those who had tried and failed last year failed just as hard now. Among those who were carried out of the room unconscious was Colin; this was not a surprise for Ginny, who hadn't really thought him the type in the first place. And absolutely no one produced a Patronus with the brilliant glow or perfect form of Harry's (or Hermione's).

"It's your turn, Miss Weasley," said Professor Lockhart. "Good luck." Ginny stepped forward, having suppressed as many of her nerves as she could.

Well, it's obvious what you are, thought Ginny, as the cloaked figure appeared before her. You're Evil. Capital-E Evil. That's what you personify. You exist to cause negative utility, you're not supposed to exist, and you even look more demonic than any other magical creature I've seen. It's not that hard to figure out. So, then, how do I solve you? Or, rather, how would Harry solve you? How would Harry solve evil?

No, no, thought Ginny. That's the wrong way to think about it altogether. You can't make a Patronus using Occlumency. The Defense Professor said so. How would I solve evil? What's my plan to deal with it? What does my worldview say? The symptoms of Dementor exposure were already sinking in. It was becoming a little harder to think, though Ginny was pushing through.

God has already dealt with you, thought Ginny. Your game is up. Your price was paid in full on the cross, and any suffering you cause can therefore only be temporary. The idea that you are still an existential threat to anyone is an illusion, and I see through that illusion. (Is something wrong? This isn't how Harry would think about this. No, push on.) I know the truth.

I believe that the Lord God created the universe, thought Ginny. I believe that He sent His only son to die for my sins. I believe that the line of Christ contains all wizardkind! You have no place here!

"Expecto Patronum!" shouted Ginny, as loudly as her lungs could currently provide. Her wand had been correctly raised, but nothing came out. She glanced diagonally downwards, otherwise frozen, expecting reality to correct itself.

What? thought Ginny. No, try again. I believe that Satan has a hold on you! I believe that the Lord God has sent me here! I believe-

Ginny finally fainted.

We didn't agree to this! We didn't agree to this! But I did... Oh God, I'm a murderer. Save me. Kill me. I need to be killed, I mustn't threaten anyone... They're dead... It's my fault... I trusted you. I'm going to wind up not remembering any of this, and I won't be able to protect anyone from myself then. Or you. The Chamber's going to keep opening, and opening, and opening, and we're going to keep killing, and killing, and killing... I did kill Cedric, after all, and now how many of his friends? You lied to me and I should have seen through it. But how, in Parseltongue - here he comes. Is Obliviation like dying?

The baby looked up at its towering parents and the healer, and they had a strange conversation using strange words that it could not understand, but could remember, somewhere in the deep recesses of its infant brain, where only the memory magic of a conceptual being could recover it, and even then, only for the purposes of torture.

"I can offer a mass Obliviation-" said the healer.

"I want my son back," said Arthur.

"Any kind of human Transfiguration is very dangerous," said the healer. "We're already very lucky that she's stabilized." Arthur made a reflexive stabbing motion that he'd picked up watching Muggle criminals who had to rely on Muggle weapons. "It would be risking the child's life all over again."

"And it's not risking the child's life to leave him like this?" said Molly, through her tears.

"No," said the healer. "Particularly given the function of eagle's splendor."

"What does eagle's splendor have to do with this?" said Molly, exactly simultaneously with her husband's similar utterance: "Who said anything about a potion of eagle's splendor?"

"Healers know things, Mr. and Mrs. Weasley," said the healer, "even if we are legally prevented from disclosing them. In most cases, at least; an exception might be made here seeing as a child was endangered. But the significance of eagle's splendor's function is that it causes the body's appearance to match the mind's ideal."

"Enough!" said Arthur. "If you can't reverse the effect, what can you do?"

"As I was saying, I can offer a mass Obliviation applied to all friends and family, everyone who'd know, so that they're unaware that your daughter was ever any different," said the healer.

"My daughter is the third seventh son," said Molly, and she practically spit. There was a pause.

"I'm sorry," said the healer. The baby looked up at its mother, who was the most upset it had ever seen her. Its mother looked back, but this did nothing to alleviate her distress; in fact, she had a look of disgust about her.

What's wrong, Mother? Why don't you recognize me? Why don't you recognize me? Why don't-

Chapter 23: Amorphous Confusion

Every human being, rationalist or not, has a reservoir in their brain where disbelief is suspended. If too much disbelief flows into that reservoir too quickly, it will burst and the brain will scramble to recreate its picture of reality from scratch. This is why, for example, a secret evil overlord who should already be the target of suspicion should not orchestrate plots that immediately appear absurd; dazzling absurd plots are only for situations where it is certain that they could not point back at oneself even vaguely. (See also: the Hogwarts third-floor corridor, 1992-06-13.)

However, the reservoir may also be burst gradually, not by rapid addition of unbelievable things in succession, but by slow addition of them, over the course of a year or a lifetime. In late March, 1993, that was happening to Ginevra Weasley; the tipping point was probably when, following Professor Sprout's untimely and horrific demise, Ginny felt strangely unwholesome, on top of simply feeling un-whole. The strange damage to Ginny – she seemed to feel it in her soul – was slowly healing, but she decided that to simply ignore and it let it heal would be malignantly stupid, so she opted to uncache some thoughts, beginning with I should speak more with Hermione instead of giving into my Ugh Curses and avoiding her. She opted to meet with Hermione after breakfast one Saturday. Hermione didn't make nearly so much of a pretense of being busy as Harry did.

"I just wanted to talk to you about the odd things that have been going on this year," said Ginny.

"There have certainly been a lot of them," said Hermione. "Harry hasn't been bothering you, has he?"

"Well..." said Ginny. "He got kind of aggressive about the whole religion thing for a couple of months, but he started to get quieter and more distant several weeks ago, and since the attack on the greenhouse, he's just been entirely withdrawn. He's even been missing meetings and having Blaise fill in for him, and it's just not the same? Blaise even read Harry's eulogy for Lesath. But mostly I wonder what Harry's up to."

"I've noticed that, too," said Hermione. "I have to be honest, I know some confidential details about what he's doing, and I can't tell you about them. But I don't even know what's been occupying him lately. He does still talk to me, but he absolutely refuses to discuss how he's spending most of his time, now. He says he'll probably tell me in a few months. I've seen some strange orders he's been filling. Odd business at the Hospital. I don't know what any of it is, though. But even if I did, I couldn't tell you."

"Huh," said Ginny. That was quite something. "That is fascinating. And probably very good news. The last couple of times Harry was up to something strange, it destroyed Azkaban and established the Peverell Family Hospital."

"The difference is that I was heavily involved in both of those things," said Hermione. "I have no idea what this is."

"All of that isn't actually what I wanted to talk to you about," said Ginny.

"Oh," said Hermione. "What is it, then? Your Patronus?"

"Oh, um, I don't have one," said Ginny. "Gave it my best shot but I guess I didn't figure out the riddle." Hermione smiled, perhaps inviting Ginny to proceed as though she hadn't asked the question. "Everything just seems wrong, lately, Hermione. To me personally, as if I'm missing something big. Not something big about the problem everyone's facing, but about the problems I'm facing, personally. Can I tell you something really secret and can you promise not to tell anyone?"

"Sure?" said Hermione, and as Hermione was thinking wait, what if it's a security concern?, Ginny was thinking what, what if she feels she has to tell people anyway because it's a security concern?

"Um, never mind," said Ginny. "What should I do if I suspect I'm being regularly Obliviated? I feel like I have big holes in my memory and my thought processes get clogged up with clouds of fog that I don't think originate from my own faulty brain."

"Oh!" said Hermione. "Harry actually taught me a pretty neat trick for this. Turns out it's useless for me because of my Sparkly Unicorn Princess powers but it should work just fine for you. If you suspect you're going to be Obliviated soon, covertly bite the inside of your lip really hard; so hard that you'll leave scar tissue for a long time. Commit to memory a long, long time in advance that if you've bitten the inside of your lip like that and don't remember doing it, you've been Obliviated. Occasionally it'll give a false positive, because humans do occasionally bite their lips in their sleep or something like that, but it should at least grant you a degree of protection."

"Brilliant," was all Ginny could say.

"It's very worrisome if you suspect you're being Obliviated, though, Ginny," said Hermione. "That's very worrisome for anyone – particularly a young girl. And that's on top of all of the other strange things that have been going on. You were one of the suspects after Professor Sprout was killed, weren't you?"

"Yes, but I was cleared," said Ginny. "I was just in the bathroom." The truth was that she had woken up in the bathroom, with a vague recollection that she had fallen asleep there, but she had realized long ago that telling anyone this would be simply disastrous.

"Alright," said Hermione, just as worried as she had been seconds ago, if not moreso. "Also, if possible – which it likely won't be – try to leave some record of what you expect to be Obliviated of, somewhere where you expect to find it."

"That's actually very convenient," said Ginny. "Thanks for pointing it out."

"No problem," said Hermione. "But if you don't mind, could you give me more specifics on why you're suspicious of your perceptions?"

"I do mind," said Ginny. "It's very private."

"Private means a lot less in times like this," said Hermione. "People are dying, anywhere and without warning."

"Didn't you read Harry's first Method of December?" said Ginny. "'On Civil Liberties and Terrorism'?"

"Yes, I did, as a matter of fact," said Hermione, "and Harry was speaking of cases like Lesath Lestrange, who were investigated and hurt without anything even mistakable for evidence. Not saying that people should hold back in finding the actual offender. This is no time or context for fooling around; what did you notice?"

"It's just some cached thoughts I need to attend to," said Ginny.

"Cached thoughts can kill people, Ginevra," said Hermione. "What kind of cached thoughts are they?"

"Well, talking to you, for one," said Ginny. "I realized a long time ago that talking to you was a good idea because of how wise and conscientious and so on you are. But I kept putting it off because I was jealous of you." Hermione seemed to assume this was flattery, and looked distinctly unimpressed. "And also, Draco."

"Draco Malfoy?" said Hermione. "He's courting you, isn't he?"

"Yes," said Ginny. "And frankly, it all seems too good to be true. I've been meaning to test him for love potions; all I've gotten round to yet is Amortentia, because that one's such an easy test because its effects are so extreme."

"He likes you too much?" said Hermione. Ginny nodded. "Ginny, that's stupid; you're hiding something, and poorly."

"Um, no?" said Ginny. "I'm not?" The truth was that Ginny absolutely was hiding something, but that didn't mean she was exaggerating about Draco. "He really is acting weird; I tolerate it because I like it, but that doesn't mean it isn't weird. Out-of-character, even."

"Anything else?" said Hermione.

"Nothing of importance," said Ginny.

"Anything else?" said Hermione, much more pointedly.

"Just that I've more or less forgotten entirely about a lot of the predictions Luna's made and told me about," said Ginny.

"Oh," said Hermione, "you can probably ignore that. Divination is a bunch of pseudomagic, it's barely any more effective than the Muggle kind that amounts to random number generators and con art. Rarely ever rationally actionable because the source of magic is so intent on playing tricks on people."

"Technically, it's against my religion," said Ginny, "but the liberalized interpretation is that that only refers to the Muggle kind, since it's dishonest. A scam instead of a science."

"Wizard Divination isn't a science, either," said Hermione. "Luna's variety least of all."

"Maybe," said Ginny.

At the scheduled time, Ginny arrived at Draco's room, and entered using the knock Draco had shown her.

"Ginny!" said Draco. "What are those?" He was obviously looking at a small medicine bottle Ginny was holding; he snapped his fingers and Dobby disappeared from the room.

"Some pills I got from Madam Pomfrey," said Ginny. "I'm testing you." Draco was taken aback.

"Testing me for what, exactly?" said Draco.

"Love potions," said Ginny.

"This again?" said Draco.

"Yes, this again," said Ginny. "It's like Luna said. If the world around you seems too good to be true, then you're still in the mirror. And you seem too good to be true, so I'm trying to figure out which mirror I'm still in."

"Luna's rubbing off on you," said Draco. Ginny half-sneezed, and passed nine large pills – three light blue, three dark blue, and three yellow – to Draco, each of which radiated nausea.

"Here goes," said Draco. "If this is what it takes to prove it to you."

"You don't have to prove anything to me, Draco," said Ginny. "I'm proving things to myself." One by one, Draco swallowed the pills, and within minutes, they reappeared in Ginny's hand, each with a horizontal green line on them.

"Alright..." said Ginny. "Good, good, good... good... You're clean. There's still of course the possibility of Legilimency or an Imperius or simply evil plotting to explain your behavior..."

"Might I ask why you're so suspicious of my behavior all of a sudden?" said Draco.

"Oh, Draco," said Ginny. "I feel that something's very, very wrong with my life, and I have no idea what that is. So I'm approaching the problem systematically. Burning every possibility at the roots."

"A grim metaphor, considering the circumstances," said Draco. "Have you considered that the problem might be Harry? He's been acting odder and odder lately."

"Well... I have," said Ginny. "Probably not enough, but I have. But what would I do about that? Harry is absolutely impenetrable, Draco. He's unapproachable, especially when he wants to be. If he's keeping secrets from me, I am absolutely not going to figure them out until he wants me to. I trust he has my best interests at heart."

"But you don't trust that I do?" said Draco.

"Well, let's face it," said Ginny. "I think I love you, but I have no idea what your motivation is. What drives you? What's your goal in this story?"

"Well, first, to survive," said Draco. "That's harder than it should be at Hogwarts lately. The Monster could be anywhere at any time, and no one really knows what's going on."

"Exactly," said Ginny.

"Second, to forget," said Draco. "I want to put the past behind me."

"But why?" said Ginny. "Who would ever want to forget anything?"

"Well, I mean metaphorically forget," said Draco.

"What does that even mean?" said Ginny, raising her voice in the tradition of the Great Interrobang of Oz. Draco stopped, and put his hand over his mouth contemplatively, before speaking.

"It means I want to have something happier to think about instead," said Draco. "A place or person to escape to."

"I'm so sorry," said Ginny. "I wasn't really considering your perspective sufficiently. Or anyone's, really. Paranoia-"

"Third – and this should really have been second. So, first and a half," said Draco, "I want to protect as many people as possible from whatever it is that's going on at Hogwarts lately. I had a feeling this would be a bad year before the threats were even issued. That's why Professor Lockhart is employed here." Ginny nodded.

"What?" asked Ginny.

"That's why he's employed here?" said Draco. "Because I contacted him to protect us? I've told you this before, I'm sure."

"I don't believe so," said Ginny. Draco appeared troubled by this.

"Tim told me that Gilderoy Lockhart could protect us from the trouble brewing at Hogwarts," said Draco.

"I'm not sure if I trust Tim," said Ginny. "Has he ever possessed you?"

"You've asked me this before," said Draco. Ginny was growing impatient. Not with Draco specifically; more with whatever force was making a riddle out of her life.

"And what did you say then?" asked Ginny.

"I let Tim possess me so he could speak to Lockhart, to persuade him to come to Hogwarts," said Draco.

"That sounds bad," said Ginny. "Very, very bad."

"But I did it to protect you," said Draco. "You and everyone. And you've got to admit that he's the best replacement for Monroe we could get."

"It just... it doesn't make sense, Draco!" said Ginny. "Something isn't right." But Ginny was already beginning to calm down, because her mind's model of Tim was telling her that she should appreciate the present more, because she never knew when everything might change. She didn't know if she'd remember this moment in years or even days, so, she figured, she should make the most of it.

"Maybe..." said Draco.

"Let's talk about something else," said Ginny.

When Luna was permitted to leave the Infirmary (not long after she was admitted), she was crying. But soon, Ginny appeared, which helped to soak up some of her tears – literally, of course; Luna cried directly into Ginny's robes. Ginny tried to calm Luna down, and finally began asking questions.

"Luna, thank God you're alright," said Ginny. "I've heard a lot of conflicting stories; what happened?"

"I was having – tea," started Luna. "With Marietta Edgecombe."

"Go on," said Ginny. "Tell me everything."

"Impossible," said Luna. "But anyway, I was baking those fortune cookies I showed you a few months ago."

"They don't work very well," said Ginny, and she immediately wondered why she'd said it. An attempt to lighten the mood? What an awful attempt.

"Yes, they do!" said Luna. "I opened mine, and the fortune was 'Run.' So I did, and I told Marietta to run too, but she must have thought I was just having a fit or something. But I could hear something coming, so I hid, and I could feel the Basilisk drawing near, and Marietta couldn't get away, and she was petrified."

"Reversibly?" said Ginny.

"Of course, but it's still awful," said Luna. "Not to mention that I think they're covering something up about the Potions of Reanimation. I think it's going to be longer than they're saying before the people can be restored. I didn't finish my story. I'm crouched in an uncomfortable position in the cabinet, hoping that the Basilisk will go away, when I hear a human voice, and it's unrecognizable because it's been deepened. And it says 'Petrificus Totalus'. And I can't move. For hours. Then we're both found, and I'm unfrozen and made to answer questions about what happened to her, and I tell them pretty much what I just told you, and then they let me go but half the school is probably going to think it's me, now! I was getting my worst marks in Herbology, and I saw Colin as a bit of a rival, and... and..."

"It's not you, Luna," said Ginny. "I have a strong feeling that the person behind all of this is going to be caught very soon, and be stopped. This is all almost over."

"How can you say that?" Luna asked, through tears. "You're not a Seer." But what Luna didn't know was that the interior of Ginny's mouth had a deep gash in it. By Ginny's bedside, furthermore, was a speck that explained in Parseltongue that she was about to take Tim to investigate the Chamber. And best of all, Ginny had firmly decided, about thirty minutes ago, never to take Tim out of his box to speak to him again.

Chapter 24: Pax Romana

Ginny had already recovered from her shock – many months ago, actually (that's the thing about being Obliviated; to some degree you can get used to a state of affairs you don't even know about). So, rather than panicking, she made a premeditated decision not to take any further action. She didn't bring Tim to the attention of the Headmistress, Harry, Hermione, or any other authorities, because, having been Obliviated, she didn't actually know how involved she was, and a legal precedent about a century old established that one is still culpable for crimes committed prior to Obliviation, even if the Obliviation was entirely unrequested.

What she did do was place Tim's box – with Tim's diary inside, and Tim inside it – under her bed, where it had normally gone before. She then heaped on top of it spare blankets, and quilts, and pillows, and anything else obscuring that didn't look out-of-place in the dorm. Her hope was that she had buried her problem (she could literally bury it over the summer), and for a while, this certainly seemed to be the case. About a month went by with a shockingly low amount of incident, and every day that thus passed simultaneously convinced Ginny that she, and everyone else, was now safe, and that she had really been at the root of the problems, by trusting Tim, all along. But no matter – it was all over, now. There was some guilt, but Ginny was mostly proud to have finally fixed the problem - particularly seeing as that's all she could actually remember doing.

On one occasion, Ginny decided to speak to Hermione about her calculator – it now fully supported multiplication and division, and could even solve basic algebra problems, if they involved only a single unknown and the four basic arithmetic functions. Doing so involved outing herself as a Parselmouth, but she suspected Harry and Hermione were close enough that she already knew that.

"I'm also strongly considering inventing a spell that will enable non-Parselmouths to make just-as-effective use of Sapespeck," said Ginny. "With more difficulty than a Parselmouth can, but still perfectly within a normal wizard's ability. The way that the new spell works is so clear in my mind that I'm sure it'll be the first thing I invent once I get a leg up on Ancient Runes, and then I'm pretty sure it'll be central to some of my N.E.W.T. projects."

"Wow," said Hermione. "I can tell you, as a Muggle who's familiar with computing - this really does have as much potential as you think – or maybe more. This is exactly the kind of thing Harry would love to hear about if he weren't so busy."

"Oh, well, I actually showed him a prototype a few months ago," said Ginny. "It wasn't as robust, but the basic idea was there. He didn't seem particularly interested."

"Ugh," said Hermione. "Something's wrong about Harry, you know? He's slowly been getting worse and worse since some time after Voldemort finally died; he's falling back into some nasty mental patterns and he barely seems to listen when I point it out. It hurts me to say this, especially seeing as Voldemort killed me, but I think he might have left a power vacuum behind that's dangerous with Harry around. I like Harry, I'm closer to him than anyone, but I think he might be getting Dark. I mean, that's a bit of a stretch, but it's just, aloof – aloof doesn't cover it."

"Maybe he's just getting smarter and smarter," said Ginny, "and he's less and less on our level."

"You know what happens to things that just get smarter and smarter," said Hermione, and Ginny shook her head. Hermione mimed an explosion, and mouthed a related onomatopoeia. Ginny rolled her eyes at this.

And they say that she's smart, thought Ginny.

"Maybe you should try to talk to him more," thought Ginny. It was hard for Ginny to spur Hermione towards Harry, but she'd attained her own happiness, and if Harry was becoming solitary and detached from reality, it was probably for the best that he get closer to his loved ones. Just look at what happened to Lesath! (Not that Harry would do that. Dying was too unappealing to him and he had too much reason to go on.)

"I've tried," said Hermione. "But maybe I should... try harder?"

"That's the spirit!" said Ginny. That sort of feel-good optimism continued to propel Ginny through the happy month with no Tim and no attacks.

On Good Friday, Ginny and several of her classmates (mostly her siblings) were granted a religious exemption enabling them to Floo home for the weekends; they were all nearly prevented thanks to "reconsiderations of the policy", but a quick visit from Molly Weasley sorted that out. On Sunday, at the Ottery St. Catchpole Eastern Samothrace Orthodox Chapel, though, Ginny received quite a surprise.

"Draco!" said Ginny.

"Ginny," said Draco.

"Draco?" said Molly.

"Mrs. Weasley?" said Draco.

"Malfoy!" said Ron, with accompanying antipathetic noises from the twins.

"Yes, you're Ginny's friend, aren't you?" said Molly.

"He sure is," said Ron, and he made a gagging noise. Molly snapped her fingers, and Ron disappeared.

"What are you doing here?" said Molly. "Aren't you still supposed to be in school?"

"Well, your daughter – Ginny," said Draco, "has been telling me about the service, and the celebration, and the history, and the story – the Creation, the Exaltation, the Manifestation, the Crucifixion, the Resurrection, the Resonance, the Metastasis."

"Precisely correct," said Percy; Draco nodded and smiled.

"So I decided I had to come visit and see," said Draco. Molly Weasley looked positively awed, proud of her daughter, a far cry from the mother who had, over winter break, delivered stern, grotesque warnings about the things young Malfoy men were known to do.

"Here's a young man who's happy to go to church on a Sunday!" said Molly. "Fred, George, you could learn a thing or two." Fred and George looked somewhere between uncomfortable and amused; Arthur and Bill were, of course, already inside. Charlie, of course, had made an excuse again not to come home this year.

Another nineteen days of public peace came and went. As far as Ginny knew, all was well.

"Obliviate! Rebliviate!"

It was a Sunday in mid-April. That was all the context Cho Chang had on where she was and why she was there. This looks like I'm leaving the Defense room, where Professor Lockhart teaches, where Professor Quirrell taught in my second year, where Professor Burbage taught in my first. What am I doing here? It's a weekend, right? Not a class day? Why can't I remember? This question was quickly painted over.

Cho realized that she was holding a scroll, so she looked down at it; it was an essay she remembered writing for Defense Against the Dark Arts, just last week. "On The Applicability Of Various Muggle Schools In Magical Combat". What was that in red above it? "T"? For "Troll"? No, that didn't make sense. The essay wasn't Cho's best work, but this was completely outside her hypothesis space. Cho slowly turned around, and saw Professor Lockhart, Gilderoy Lockhart, sitting at his desk, staring up at her as she was about to leave, and she realized that she was about to leave because she'd gotten nervous about confronting the Defense Professor.

"Miss Chang?" said Professor Lockhart. "Is there something you wish to discuss with me?"

"Um..." said Cho, and she couldn't back down now. She just couldn't. It had to be his mistake, it had to, that or she'd made a drastic, drastic mistake. Either Professor Lockhart had mistakenly written the wrong mark, or she had made a colossal error of judgment somewhere in writing. Professor Lockhart was too smart, he couldn't actually make a bad judgment. How had Cho screwed up so badly? "Yes." And she'd thought Professor Lockhart had seen potential in her! He was taking her on quests! Quests of meaningful importance for the wellbeing of all of Hogwarts!

"Is there a problem?" said Lockhart.

"Um, yes," said Cho, walking down the steps towards him. "It's about my essay..."

"Ah," said Lockhart, and he waited for Cho to arrive at his desk.

"Is this a 'T' for 'Troll'?" said Cho.

"Yes," said Lockhart. "They were going to rename it 'Terrible' out of respect, but Miss Granger insisted they were being overly sensitive." A million thoughts ran through Cho's head, and finally one came out:

"What did I do?" asked Cho.

"Apparently not a good essay!" said Professor Lockhart, more in disgust than humor. "I wrote notes in the margins pointing out some of your more egregious errors."

"What?" said Cho. "Oh." She felt very stupid, not to have noticed them. Or – she did, and then she just forgot about them. Yes, glancing down, it was a miserable essay, and she could barely believe she'd turned it in and expected any better. She must have been half asleep. It still didn't make sense. Why had she even come here to complain? Why was she even still permitted to breathe air? "We went on quests," Cho stuttered. The Defense Professor stared at her, and blinked.

"Are you suggesting you should therefore be subjected to nepotism?" said Lockhart. "Because if so, you insult me and my integrity."

"I'm sorry!" said Cho. "It's just, I just - I want it to disappear. I know I can't. I made my bed and now I have to lie in it. It's fair, life's fair, but I want this to go away." She shook the scroll desperately, and this time, Professor Lockhart did laugh, albeit darkly.

"All Ravenclaw girls are the same," said Professor Lockhart, with a sneer. "They want extra credit here, they want a chance to rewrite a shameful term paper there. They don't want to work hard for it in the first place like a Hufflepuff, and they're not brave enough to accept their mistake like a Gryffindor, and they don't want anything grander like a Slytherin. Just a little slip of paper that affirms that they're Really Smart." Cho tried to object, but she knew she wasn't supposed to. She had a feeling that Lockhart was right, anyway.

"Although," continued Professor Lockhart, "I'll confess that most Ravenclaw girls who come to me with sob stories have papers better than this." He seized the scroll from the spot on his desk where Cho had set it, so that she could sob into her hands. "So I expected most of the class to perform decently on the assignment, so I didn't see any problem, tying such a large portion of the class marks to it. This assignment is simply necessary for perfect course performance. With a T? At least two full course grades down." This was not alleviating Cho's crying in the least. "You really are in trouble, Miss Chang. Worse than you'd imagined, I'd wager."

"But..." said Lockhart, and the scroll vanished from his hand. "I can erase it from the record." It came back. "Or I could do what I'm supposed to. But I'm not altogether opposed to the idea. I do care for you, Cho – at least in some sense. And there's something I'd be willing to trade for my good marks." Lockhart smiled, and Cho was just confused. What was he leading up to?

"Another quest to avenge Cedric?" said Cho.

"A quest of sorts," said Lockhart. "To forget Cedric."

How Dark was the Defense Professor, exactly? Were they about to set off for some haunted cottage filled with the screams of the damned?

"Would you believe that the quarters assigned to the Defense Professor are immediately behind this classroom?" said Lockhart. "They moved it here when Professor Quirrell moved the classes. Actually, Professor Monroe. Actually... I would speculate he was actually Voldemort - or at least my friends in high places would."

"What a horrible thing to say," said Cho. "But - what friends in high places? It's an intriguing possibility; is it related-"

"Shut up," said Lockhart. "I got off track. This conversation is about you... your marks... what you're worth... and me. Follow me." Professor Lockhart beckoned towards the dwellings behind the Defense Hall, and Cho followed, because she believed she had nowhere else to go.

It proceeded that Cho was Obliviated about three more times that day, before finally leaving the classroom with a perfect essay (the one she had actually written), no recollection of any other essay, and a nice story about how she and Professor Lockhart had gone and confronted giants over their possible trafficking of cockatrice eggs, which could potentially have been used for the recent attacks.

Chapter 25: Occam's Razor, Pt 1

It moved.

It's probably not physically possible. It wasn't physically possible, it couldn't possibly be physically possible. And yet Ginny could feel, like in the story about The Princess And The Doxy Egg, that there were less things under her bed than there were supposed to be. And like in that fable, she would soon be set upon by doxies – or worse.

Where was Tim? Where was he? Ginny quickly tore apart the mountain of blankets beneath her bed, and confirmed that the box was empty. Someone had taken Tim out of his box, and Ginny didn't know where they'd put him.

Had Ginny been possessed and Obliviated recently? She didn't know. It was the middle of the afternoon and she was lying on her bed and she couldn't quite remember when she'd gotten here. Her lip wasn't freshly wounded, but perhaps this time she had been actively prevented from marking herself thus; simply being surprised with physical contact with the diary and being mentally overpowered to the extent that she had no control whatsoever over her body ought to do it.

Ginny's eyes shot to Pansy Parkinson, who was sitting on her bed adjacent to Ginny's, brushing her hair, poorly. No, the diary wasn't anywhere nearby. Then where was it?

Tim – Diary – Box – Draco?

Ginny was soon running to the boys' dormitories, and then to Draco's private room. A quick knock (the secret one Draco had shown her) opened the door, and revealed that he was studying – but mildly, though pleasantly, confused by Ginny's presence.

"Ginny!" said Draco. "What is it?"

"Where is Tim?" said Ginny, firm punctuation after each word.

"You lost him?" said Draco, appalled.

"No, wand-shard," said Ginny, who had no time for nonsense today. "He escaped somehow."

"...what?" said Draco.

"What is Tim?" said Ginny.

"He's a book," said Draco. "He can't escape."

"What is he?" said Ginny. "You know better than I do; you're where he came from. Sorry, I skipped over something – he's what was petrifying people."

"What?" said Draco. "No, that's – what evidence do you have?" He'd gone from bored to sweating in nothing flat.

"I began to suspect I was being Obliviated," said Ginny, "so I began taking precautionary measures. And then one day I wake up to discover that I've sent myself a signal that I'm afraid I'm about to be Obliviated, and I don't remember sending it. So I check in a predesignated location, and I've recorded a message for myself in Parseltongue that I'm about to let Tim possess me and investigate the Chamber. And I don't remember recording the message and I don't remember being possessed. And then I find out Marietta Edgecombe's just been petrified. So I get the general idea that something's up, you know?"

Draco was just repeating "oh God" over and over again in various intonations.

"I immediately shut him in his box and pledged to myself not to open it, and there haven't been any attacks since," said Ginny.

"So-" started Draco.

"So I think I was right," said Ginny, "and now Tim's disappeared. Someone rifled through my things and removed him, I think, and they put everything back in order but I could feel that it had happened. I think I've been Obliviated again. This is a disaster. Tell me everything you know about Tim."

"I had some idea that my father got him from the Dark Lord," said Draco, "but I didn't update on that once I realized that he was just out-and-out evil and didn't have any of our best interests in mind and wouldn't give someone a gift just to reward them. They always have catches! Like the silver hand he gave Fenrir Greyback!"

"Yeah, strangled him, I know," said Ginny. "And I knew Tim came from Voldemort. But he said he was made out of an unwilling test subject, and now he hated Voldemort and wanted to act against him."

"The Dark Lord wouldn't create a being that could turn against him," said Draco. "And Tim didn't tell me anything like that; he just said he was named Tim. There wasn't any backstory, not as far as he provided. He just listened to me talk about my problems, and responded with support. Sometimes he gave advice, and sometimes he indicated that he had some basic background about the wizarding world, but he needed me to update him on any new current events that happened. Eventually he convinced me to consent to possession, but as far as I could tell, he only ever did things while I was possessed that I already wanted, so I was just thankful for it."

"Do you have a perfect memory of being possessed?" said Ginny.

"Of course not!" said Draco. "Tim explained to me that being possessed impairs your ability to form memories. I only remember the fadeout."

"That's not what he told me," said Ginny. "In fact, he told me he had no ability to make me anything less than fully aware while possessed, and he told me in a magic way that prevented him from lying."

"What, did he make an Unbreakable Vow to you?" said Draco.

"No, he spoke to me in Parseltongue," said Ginny. "I'm a Parselmouth, and you can't lie in Parseltongue. Of course, it eventually turned out I was being Obliviated, so I guess he was twisting the truth..."

"The Dark Lord was a Parselmouth," said Draco. "He'd use it to control his pet snake – of course, she's long since dead, thank God; she was even more antagonistic with the Death Eaters than he was." Ginny and Draco stared at each other uncomfortably.

"Could Tim be the Dark Lord in some way?" asked Ginny.

"Maybe," said Draco. "It sounds like the kind of thing you'd find in a tome of eldritch lore, coming back to life through your own talking diary."

"We're both such idiots," said Ginny. "It's so obvious. The conditions your father told you that you should open Tim under – did they sound a lot like 'once Voldemort is apparently as far as anyone can tell one hundred percent dead'?"

"No," said Draco. "...yes." Ginny made a vocal sound that fulfilled the same purpose as an expletive but was not a coherent linguistic expression. "I see what you're saying. It's the only way anything makes sense; I became sentimentally attached to Tim, but his entire existence only makes sense if he's actually the Dark Lord. We're in trouble."

"The question is just, what does he want with the Chamber of Secrets, and why is he attacking people?" said Ginny.

"And where is he?" said Draco.

"That's what I was asking you!" said Ginny.

"I don't know," said Draco.

"You don't know," said Ginny, "and I don't know, so where is he? Who else could possibly have him? Luna? I remember loaning Tim to Luna once, but she said she didn't let him possess it. They actually didn't get along with each other at all, so that didn't make sense."

"You loaned Tim out?" said Draco.

"Yeah, I know, I'm an idiot," said Ginny.

"To Luna?" said Draco, still indignant.

"I know," said Ginny, more indignant still.

"Don't hiss at me," said Draco.

"Sorry," said Ginny, and she blushed. "Who else?

"Hmm..." said Draco.

"The Defense Professor is suspicious because he's the Defense Professor," said Ginny, "among other reasons, which admittedly aren't very significant, like how no one's sure where he lived for a decade after the war, and how he's so much more skilled than everyone who knew him remembered, and now he's acting as a mysterious old wizard for heroes-to-be - but it's all technically possible for someone who went off and independently studied for a decade; he's frankly pretty similar to Monroe. And I can't think of any connection he has to Tim."

"You're right," said Draco.

"Harry's been acting weird lately," said Ginny. "Maybe we should check him."

"Okay," said Draco. "What about Hermione?"

"Well, she's been normal," said Ginny, "but maybe that's exactly the act she'd be putting on if she were up to something. Good point. The Headmistress?"

"Now we're just getting silly," said Draco. "Everyone can't be Tim. We need to narrow it down to the most likely-"

A soft echo of the hard scream of a prefect, rebounded through the corridors:

"Granger's been petrified!"

Chapter 26: Occam's Razor, Pt 2

"Draco, we need to go out and find out what happened," said Ginny. "Find every clue we can."

"Clues?" said Draco. "Ginny, this isn't a Necronomicon Grey story. We're not Ravenclaws using our vast command of trivia to solve a mystery that's actually just a half-baked riddle. We're children in a war zone who just heard that someone was murdered. Temporarily. Hopefully."

"Still better to find out what's going on," said Ginny, and she turned to leave.

"If you're going, I'm going with you," said Draco. "You have to be safe." Ginny smiled at a job well done and fed her brain's "exploitation of chivalry" program a biscuit.

"Where was Hermione petrified?" Ginny called out to a prefect.

"Our secondary girls' bathroom, actually," said the prefect.

"Ginny," whispered Draco.

"What," whispered Ginny.

"That's where they killed a girl forty years ago," said Draco.

"Oh," said Ginny. She considered this. "Write down notes about everything we find out – actually, write notes about everything we already know, too. In case our progress is reset by Obliviation. Since that's clearly on the table."

"Got it," said Draco, and he'd already summoned a cloud of floating parchment scraps more typical of a Ravenclaw in finals week than a paranoid Slytherin.

"I wonder if anything Tim told me in Parseltongue actually matters," said Ginny. "If Obliviation is on the table, the False Memory Charm probably is too. Maybe he never actually said any of the things that I'm counting on memories of him saying. He just made me think that he said them after the fact."

"You're going to go cross-eyed like that," said Draco, scrambling to move his quill from scrap to scrap, writing sentence-fragment notes he thought he'd understand without further context. "Wait, I'm not allowed in - ?" They'd reached the enormous entrance to the girls' lavatory, which had already flooded with staff and students alike – strange, seeing as few normally used it except in those outlier times when the the regular restroom was overloaded.

"Neah, they removed the wards on the girls' bathrooms years ago," said Ginny. "You aren't going to get pregnant by going in there. Anymore. Come on." She physically pulled Draco past the threshold, and then they saw Hermione.

In her Petrification, she was made equal to any other human. Her phoenix, it would later be determined, had entered the stratosphere and gone dormant besides Dumbledore's. She showed no signs of supernatural powers; she radiated no aura of purity. She was not Hermione. She was a structure of inert stone that looked something like Hermione. She had clearly been knocked over post-petrification; she was lying in an uncomfortable position beneath a stained-glass window. Standing above her was the Headmistress.

"Out, out!" cried the Headmistress. "Unless you have something to discuss with me, out! We are investigating a serious crime; this is not a show for public entertainment! I am holding Miss Granger's safety goggles in my hands; they functioned correctly and I assure all of you that she will make a full recovery simultaneously with Colin Creevey and Marietta Edgecombe!" Draco and Ginny glanced at each other, certain that they wanted to stay, but uncertain whether they wanted to describe their reasons why to the Headmistress. Pansy waved at Draco and Ginny, for some reason. At that point, Harry appeared, his hands reddened and the tips of his sleeves singed off by some magic.

"Hermione!" said Harry, with a distress that echoed that he'd felt when he'd truly thought her dead, though this was of course a lesser distress. "Headmistress McGonagall, please let me see the goggles?"

"Of course, Mr. Potter," said the Headmistress, and Harry walked quickly to her, took the goggles from her outstretched arms, and carefully examined them. They were correctly shaded Patronus-white, and he was satisfied.

"Petrification is even more of a nasty business than I thought," said Harry. "The Diary is nonresponsive." Ginny elbowed Draco to make him write something down, and then spoke up loudly and perhaps unwisely.

"Diary?" asked Ginny. Several people, mostly people who were supposed to already be out of the room, stared at her.

"What are you-" started the Headmistress, but Harry cut her off.

"It's a unique magical artifact," said Harry. "Very secret."

"There's no chance that it's been in my possession, is there?" said Ginny.

"No," said Harry. "I'm the only one who's ever possessed it; your diary is just some sickle-store enchanted amusement, Ginny - please leave; we're investigating this and we'd prefer to be free of distractions." Ginny and Draco started to set off, but then - "Hey! Draco! Stick around, would you? It could be useful to have an outside perspective."

"I'm here on Miss Weasley's behalf," said Draco.

"Oh," said Harry. He considered this. "You can both stay. For a while. Headmistress, it goes without saying that you've attempted to use a time-turner already?"

"Yes," said the Headmistress, "and it was successful, but she'd already been petrified six hours ago."

"Damn," said Harry. "Does no one ever use this restroom?"

"It's unlucky," said Pansy, who had lingered. "A girl died here and the Dark Lord was born."

"Pansy, get out of here," said Harry; as she left Harry stretched his face with his hands out of frustration. "Superstitious people can be so draining, Headmistress."

"There are more draining people out there, Mr. Potter," said the Headmistress. Harry looked rather offended by the comment but said nothing.

"Headmistress, look!" said Harry. "Hermione was carrying a note." Harry carefully excavated a slip of paper from Hermione's rock-hard grip, and speedily read it.

"Did she leave us some hint as to the identity of the perpetrator?" said the Headmistress.

"Of course not," said Harry. "If she knew, she surely would have come to us immediately. I mean, there's a chance, but - I think this note tells us how she was lured here, though. It's in her handwriting, but I don't think she wrote it; I think she was supposed to think she wrote it. Spimster wickets."

"Ah," said the Headmistress.

"It told her to come to this bathroom, look at a particular window, and turn time back three hours to see a hint that would lead her to discover the Chamber," said Harry. "I'd assume the Monster was staring right where she was going to be. Then they must have moved the body and made it invisible so she wouldn't bump into it."

"That does fit with the evidence, yes," said the Headmistress.

"The worst part is that I developed a system, and taught it to her, specifically to protect against this," said Harry. "How it was subverted, I don't know. There's a clear password in the message, but the message was clearly designed to get her to the exact spot and time to be petrified."

"Would public knowledge of the system make it insecure?" said the Headmistress.

"I don't see how," said Harry. "It involves coming up with a password every morning, and then not telling anyone else that password, ever. She's a perfect Occlumens, too; you know that." The Headmistress was dumbfounded by this.

"Confundus," said the Headmistress.

"What?" said Harry. "Oh-!" He immediately seemed nauseated.

"This is all so complicated!" shouted Ginny.

"Ginny, you are welcome to leave if this is troubling you," said Harry.

"No," said Ginny. "I don't mean too complicated for me to understand. I mean, too complicated for our collective understanding to be correct. This is a plot with too many moving parts!"

"Tragedy of Light," muttered Draco.

"It might appear that way to us," said Harry. "But there's clearly someone playing on a deeper level than us. They've managed to avoid capture thus far, after all."

"We're clearly not dealing with someone rational," said Ginny. "In fact, I'd go so far as to say that we're dealing with someone tetched in the head."

"One to talk," said Harry.

"Potter," said Draco, sharply.

"If your plot requires more than three things to go right, you're absolutely nuts," said Ginny.

"And if it requires three things, you're at least a bit nuts," added Draco.

"I have no idea who benefits from any of this," said Ginny. "Seeing as the declared motive, breaking the Interdict, is impossible, and this plot doesn't do anything Interdict-related, there's no motive! Nuts!"

"Dumbledore would often orchestrate elaborate plots that didn't seem to have any rhyme or reason tot hem," said Harry. "But the truth was that he knew exactly what he was doing, better than any of us, because he had access to much more information. We shouldn't assume insanity in our enemy, especially when they keep winning. Don't complain about the unworthiness-"

"People still thought Dumbledore was insane," complained Ginny, "and he showed quite a few signs of it. It was the rational view to hold at the time. We should be looking for someone insane."

"I disagree," said Harry, and then someone loudly interjected:

"I'm Pansy Parkinson!" said Pansy, who had just strolled back into the room with a wide smile. All eyes went to her, and there was an extended pause of realization.

"Polyfluis Reverso!" shouted three adults at once, and Pansy turned out to be none other Luna Lovegood.

"How surprising," said Professor Lockhart, with thick sarcasm.

What? thought Ginny.

"Expecto Patronum!" said the Headmistress. "Find Pansy Parkinson and ask where she is."

"Um – ignore everything I just said," said Harry, to Ginny.

"Pansy Parksinson says, 'mmph mmph mmph mmph'!", said Minerva's Patronus. Aurors had already appeared to take Luna away for questioning; she turned straight at Ginny, mad with laughter:

"You're next, love," said Luna. "I'll get you from a thousand miles away! You're next!"

Chapter 29: Autonomy

As was expected, Luna Lovegood was cleared of all charges leveled against her, and her framing was added to the list of the true culprit's crimes. Unexpectedly, though, Luna Lovegood did not return to Hogwarts; she was given an individualized break from coursework and added to the same summer school makeup plan the Petrification victims were on. Hogwarts staff described the reason for this as a "family crisis". What actually happened was that Xenophilius Lovegood, Luna's father, had attempted, entirely unsuccessfully, to break into Nurmengard to rescue his daughter. The ensuing investigation, which made the front page of the Daily Prophet for about a week, revealed extensive, undeniable evidence that Mr. Lovegood had been behind a wide assortment of previously unsolved serious magical crimes spanning decades. He wrote a final issue of the Quibbler, but it did not reach publication – his printing presses were confiscated as evidence, and the golems of Nurmengard were not willing to provide him with use of their own.

Xenophilius received multiple life sentences, and Luna became a ward of Hogwarts; Xenophilius's will, which stated that, should anything happen to him, guardianship of Luna should pass on to Queen Elizabeth of Muggle England, was widely regarded as absurd. For the final months of her first year, Luna was placed by the Headmistress in solitary confinement in St. Mungo's, supposedly for her own good and recovery. Just thinking about it made Ginny angry; she wanted to point out that maybe the best thing for someone's mental health wasn't locking them away from social interaction for months on end. She brought it up with the APSC, and they expressed interest, but apparently never moved anything forward.

It was such a shame, too, because Ginny really, really wanted to talk to Luna. She was the single person most relevant to Ginny's recent personal revelations, after all. Draco had sworn not to tell anyone about it (or, for that matter, about anything else learned in the Chamber), but Ginny knew precisely whose name had come out of her mouth, and she knew just enough about psychology to know that it was the sort of thing the otherwise absurd aphorism "there are no accidents" was invented to describe. How exactly did she feel about Luna, then? There had to be some emotional attachment; Ginny noted that on the basis of otherwise-accountable-for utility alone, she would have pushed Luna away long, long ago. That didn't mean it was romantic, did it?

Deep down, there was some part of Ginny that intuitively believed that Luna was never, ever going to go away and stop being a part of Ginny's life, and its reaction to this was somewhere between annoyance and comfort. Maybe it was for the best that Luna wasn't available to talk to. If it really was a romance, then it was wrong, and Ginny knew it. Not wrong for moral reasons, the way some of her elders would have described it, but wrong in the way that it's wrong to believe wrong things or use wrong strategies. Luna's own sense of romance was clearly wrong, as she liked Ginny, and, according to her, girls in general, which wasn't how it was supposed to work. Now it was looking like, on some subconscious level, Ginny's sense of romance was wrong, too, which was a disaster, and Ginny didn't understand how it'd happened. Had Luna somehow infected her with something? There was a noted correlation between queerness and vampirism; perhaps they worked the same way, too. In any case, Ginny actually liked it, but hated that she liked it, and it was this latter feeling that provided her with a continuing sense of pride and identity.

Here came Harry, and Ginny was satisfied that she was done talking with herself. He looked strangely surprised, moreso than Ginny had ever seen him before, even when he was being informed of deaths in Hogwarts.

"Ginny!" said Harry. "I owe you so many apologies. Honesst."

"For what?" said Ginny.

"For underestimating you," said Harry. "Everyone's heard the news, most of all me."

"What news?" said Ginny. Had her escapades in the chamber somehow leaked? That would be disastrous.

"Surviving a Lethifold attack?" said Harry. "Inventing an advanced Patronus on the spot?"

"Oh," said Ginny. You knew you were having an interesting month when an attempt on your life slipped your mind. "Thanks, but actually, I invented it a while ago." She hoped he'd ask her how she'd done it.

"I suspected as much," said Harry. "Make sure not to tell anyone how you cast it, not even me. Knowledge of advanced Patronuses is magically dangerous to pass on to other people."

"Oh," said Ginny. "Okay. That's what I was already doing."

"Don't get me wrong, though," said Harry. "I'd love to learn it from you; it has properties my own Patronus is incapable of. I think it might be able to disassemble a Nundu by itself."

"So I've been told," said Ginny, "but I'd really rather never meet a Nundu."

"Point taken," said Harry, "but if one forms, you'd be my first contact."

You don't even wear contacts, said Ginny's internal Luna, whose (newfound?) existence was distressing.

"What I'm leading up to is, you've got to have something going for you, if you can do that," said Harry. "Something I missed. Would you accept an opportunity to become Vice President of the More Sane Squad again?"

"Oh, since Blaise has gotten petrified?" said Ginny. "That makes sense. Sure." It had been painful to tell Draco that even after the diary's destruction, more attacks were coming, but he'd accepted it, seeing as they would all be reversible and in the end the whole sordid business would fade away all the same.

"Then you're tentatively reinstated," said Harry. "Congratulations, and I look forward to your lectures on computing. I've been reading up on the theory, but only you're actually doing anything about it."

"Wait a minute," said Ginny. This is an awfully convenient arrangement, and I notice that I am confused. "I know about the thing where you can't lie in Parseltongue. Could you please confirm that you aren't the one opening the Chamber? And don't try ambiguous wording tricks with me; I know about those."

"Okay," said Harry. "I have been in the Chamber oncce, reccently, though I have vissited ssecret passsagess around it many timess. Have never sspoken to the Monsster. Wass unaware of all attackss thiss year until after they happened. I now know who hass been caussing attackss, and that they are now dead."

"You do?" said Ginny, meekly.

"Yes, and Ginny, you don't need to feel guilty at all," said Harry. "You did the right thing, and even the smartest man in the world could fall for Voldemort in a clever disguise. For an entire year, even." Ginny pouted. "I'm serious! It was known to happen in the war."

"But how do you know what I did?" said Ginny.

"I'm sorry, I can't tell you," said Harry. "It's a matter of national security."

"Hermione said you told her that all the time about things it obviously didn't apply to," said Ginny.

"Then she apparently needs to sort out her priorities as regards existential threats," said Harry. "I suppose I'll have some words for her when she's reanimated."

"Harry," said Ginny, very suddenly and, she knew, inexplicably, "am I a girl or a boy?"

"Binary gender is the map, not the territory," said Harry. "Have you ever read 'Man & Woman, Boy & Girl' by Dr. John Money?"

"No," said Ginny.

"Neither have I," said Harry. "But I'd assume it's a good starting point if you intend to investigate that sort of thing. It's the foremost scientific textbook on gender."

That doesn't sound very helpful, thought Ginny.

"Thank you," said Ginny. "That sounds very helpful. Sorry to get sidetracked like that."

"Not a problem," said Harry. "I won't tell anyone about you and Voldemort and the Chamber, by the way. Don't see anything to gain from it."

"I actually have another point I'd like to clarify with you regarding the Chamber," said Ginny.

"Yes?" said Harry.

"If you knew I killed Tim-" started Ginny.

"Tim?" said Harry.

"It's the alias the diary used," said Ginny. "Timothy Quagmire." Harry found this very funny, and was not afraid to show it.

"Sorry," said Harry. "It's a Voldemort in-joke. Go on."

"And since obviously you were aware that Blaise was attacked," said Ginny, "does that mean you were also aware that three final attacks were prescheduled?"

"Yes," said Harry. "Two are left now, and I'm going to be glad when they're over. People just don't think well in a state of fear."

"At least they'll ultimately be harmless," suggested Ginny with a smile.

Fred and George were found petrified together. They were standing in the same corridor, but faced in nearly opposite directions. The evidence suggested they were petrified simultaneously; neither seemed to have noticed and reacted to the other's Petrification. The worst part was that only Fred (assuming they were wearing their own clothes instead of switching, which was a bit of an assumption) had fogged-up goggles. According to the healers, it was possible that this was because of the connection between magical twins, and it was therefore possible that Fred's goggles could be used to cure both of them, but they had never seen a case like this before and were venturing into unknown territory. Upon hearing of this, the Patils added to the growing number of families to pull their children from Hogwarts. The school was looking emptier and emptier.

On this particular day, Ginny wasn't in Hogwarts either. The Headmistress was still holding fast against the APSC's proposal to allow permanent free Floo travel in and out of Hogwarts to students, but had, on Molly's request, allowed the Weasley children to convene for a weekend at the Burrow in their time of crisis. For once, Ginny was glad to be with her family at home - Harry and Draco, who both knew the degree to which she could be considered responsible, had given her sympathetic looks but not said a word.

"I pray for Fred's soul and for George's soul," said Molly. "They're both such rebellious boys, Lord, and only You and they know if they ultimately accepted the gift of Life. I can only hope that they applied their Gryffindor courage correctly, against sin, and beg You to forgive them as You would forgive me. In the Lord's name. Amen." Every Weasley present muttered their own "amen", and the ceremony could easily give off the false impression.

"We don't know if they're dead," said Ron.

"True," said Molly, "and that is quite a happy thought. But we don't know if they're not, and I fear for their souls either way. I'm remembering every time I ever heard them say something disrespectful in church, and I just scolded them to make them quiet instead of trying to fix them... And I feel so guilty, because they might be paying the ultimate price right now for my failure to take the situation seriously."

"Hell," said Ginny.

"Yes," said Molly.

"Do you really think God is going to send people to Hell for making an incorrect assessment of whether He exists?" said Ginny. "That doesn't sound very omnibenevolent to me."

"Do you want to go to Hell, Ginny?" said Arthur.

"No," said Ginny, "but I don't believe in it."

"Gi- Ginevra Weasley!" said Molly.

"Only one man paid the ultimate price for sin; His name was Jesus Christ, and that's a pretty important point in Wizard Christianity, I understand," said Ginny. "I'm not an atheist, mother! I've talked to atheists long enough to know that! I'm not even an agnostic! I'm a Wizard Christian like you! But you have to pick and choose your beliefs!" Ginny stood up and left the table; she would later be unsure why she'd opted to make a scene. "That's rationality!"

"Um, Ginny," said Percy, as Ginny passed, "no, it really isn't-"

"You have to pick and choose your beliefs so that they make sense!" Ginny yelled as she exited the room.

The door to the childrens' bedroom opened, and Molly stepped in.

"Hello," said Ginny, looking out a window.

"Do you know what you did wrong?" said Molly.

"Yes, mum," said Ginny.

"Explain it to me," said Molly.

"I lashed out at you and had a temper tantrum and stormed off without finishing my dinner," said Ginny. "It seems pretty simple."

"That's all correct," said Molly, "but you also defied my authority, and your father's, and, worst of all, you defied the authority of God. God isn't a good enemy to make. He's just about the most powerful enemy you can make. And I know that you know better."

"I'm sorry," said Ginny. "I really thought I was defending God. I thought I was doing the right thing."

"Half the sins in the world are committed by people who think they're doing the right thing, Ginny," said Molly. "That doesn't excuse them. You have to actually do the right thing."

"But how do you know you're really doing the right thing?" said Ginny.

"You just know," said Molly, and Ginny instantly grew tired of that thread of the conversation.

"I have a question I'd like to ask you," said Ginny.

"What is it?" said Molly.

"At the beginning of the school year," said Ginny, "I had some trouble getting into the girls' dorms. The school fixed it, but it turned out the wards were seeing me as male. I kind of dismissed it, but I've been having some strange thoughts lately." About other girls. "Do you know anything about that?"

"Oh... Ginny..." started Molly, and she was just lightly starting to cry. "The school told me when it happened. They told me to talk to you about it, and I thought that was so stupid, because if you wanted to talk about it you'd come to me. And now, here you are. Do you really want to know?"

"Yes," said Ginny, and Molly sighed.

"I guess this story starts during the war," said Molly. "I saved Lily Potter's life - she wasn't married yet, she was Lily Evans then. And anyways, she felt she had to repay me, so she gave me a gift. She tried to make it seem like a small thing; she said she just had some extra lying around. But it wasn't a small thing at all, it was huge; it was one of the rarest and most potent Potions in the world: Enhanced Eagle's Splendor. Grants the drinker permanent beauty. The stuff Veela are made of. The single dose she gave us was worth more than all the money I'd ever seen in my life. We never did know what to do with it, so we just stored it. And then we had you. You were a boy."

"It was the height of the war," continued Molly. "You know that. And then one day, when you were just two months old, we heard that James and Lily had died protecting their baby, but there'd been a miracle, and Voldemort was struck down when he tried to harm the child. It was the end of the war. The first Harry Potter day. And, as many did that day, we - shamefully - became intoxicated. I can hardly follow the reasoning we used then, but I think we decided we had to finally use the Eagle's Splendor, to 'honor Lily'. So we poured it over you."

"The healers told us you nearly died," said Molly, "but you didn't, thank God. But - when the Potion was done reshaping your body, you were a beautiful baby girl. And you've been a girl ever since. The healers offered to Obliviate the entire extended family, and we took them up on it. None of your brothers know, not uncle Bilius, not aunt Lynn, no one except your father, me, and you now. I once thought you'd never have to know; I was wrong."

"That would make me the third seventh son," said Ginny.

"If your soul is still male," said Molly, "then yes, I believe it does. We haven't been certain for years; we were certain when you were born. You were baptized as Gilderoy Aaron Weasley."

"Ginevra," said Ginny. "Mother, do you know what happened to me about a month ago?"

"The Lethifold attack," said Molly. "Of course I know about that; you know I know about that. I was up all night giving the Headmistress a piece of my mind for not giving Hogwarts the same unicorn-based protection they gave that new hospital, especially when the school is directly under attack by forces who specifically want to harm students."

"All of that's true," said Ginny, "but something else happened. I survived the Lethifold attack, using my own Patronus." Something clicked in Ginny's mother, and she calmly, curiously spoke.

"You told me you couldn't cast a Patronus," said Molly.

"Department of Mysteries made me say that, mum," said Ginny. "My Patronus was unique, like Harry's, but not, and they wanted it to stay secret as long as possible. My Patronus is fueled by my specific faith in an all-powerful, fundamentally good creator, God, to save every one of us. I am the third seventh son, mother. And I will rebuild the church and bring wizardkind back to the light. Expecto Patronum." Ginny's wand began to spark with white particles, and Molly looked on in awe.

It was the true end of the school year. Exams were over, everything was wrapping up, and the school had even temporarily assented to the APSC's "Open Hogwarts" initiative, so the halls were generally deserted. Ginny was nonetheless in school (so was Percy; Ron decided to go home early), mostly waiting for the final attack to come, to give her peace of mind. While taking a walk through Hogwarts, she encountered a substantially older Ravenclaw student, who she nonetheless knew: Penelope Clearwater.

"Ginny!" said Penelope, and it rapidly became apparent that, despite being pleased to see Ginny, she was absolutely enraged in general. Ginny wasn't sure why. "Thanks for the advice." Her hand went up to her jaw.

"You're welcome, but what advice?" said Ginny.

"The lip advice," said Penelope. "It worked for my friends, too."

"Oh!" said Ginny. "That advice. I got it from Hermione, actually, and she got it from Harry."

"I've passed it on to some of the younger girls, too," said Penelope, "but hopefully they won't need it, because Gilderoy Lockhart is getting sacked."

"Oh," said Ginny. It was strange to learn who your secret namesake was and that they were actually a horrible person within a single month.

"I'm forming an organized party to perform watchout duty on each other, in case he's hiding by the Headmistress's office to Obliviate Maxima us when we come by," said Penelope.

"Contact McGonagall by Patronus, first," said Ginny. "He can't intercept that."

"Can't cast one," said Penelope.

"Never mind," said Ginny.

Headmistress McGonagall was of course properly horrified by the evidence-backed allegations she was presented with, but discovered, to her further horror, that Gilderoy Lockhart had anticipated this and fled the school. Soon, every magical law enforcement agency in the world was memorizing his face, but the man-hunt proved unsuccessful. He was still nowhere to be found the next day, when Draco Malfoy was petrified and everything somehow got worse.

Chapter 30: Standing on the Shoulders of Giants, Pt 1

Wait a minute, thought Ginny. What? She hadn't expected Draco to be the final victim at all; if anything, he was the only person she'd ruled out. The attacks had all been arranged by Voldemort; these last three weeks in advance. And Voldemort's plan, according to the Basilisk, who had read his mind, was to permanently occupy Draco's body, and to kill Harry and frame him for the attacks. How would Draco being petrified square with that?

Could another Parselmouth have ordered an attack? Ginny seriously doubted that Ron had done such a thing; he hated Draco, but he hated speaking in Parseltongue, too, and surely wouldn't have found or used the Chamber. Harry was another possibility, but he was such a supreme rationalist that it was doubtful he'd be violent in that way, and on top of that, Ginny couldn't think of a motive. A further possibility, which simply hadn't occurred to her at first, was that Voldemort had deliberately targeted the body he thought he would be in, so that he could foil the attack and add to his false heroic narrative. Without Voldemort in Draco's body planning a defense, the attack wouldn't be foiled, and would instead proceed as the Basilisk planned it.

"Narcissa Malfoy innut gon'ter be happy about this," said Rubeus Hagrid, Hogwarts' half-giant groundskeeper, who was carrying Draco out of the school, through the front door, towards a safe storage facility.

"Mr. Hagrid, the potions are nearly ready," said Professor Slughorn, who was trailing behind him. "Draco will be as good as new within a fortnight."

"There're whispers about the school might close," said Hagrid. "Most've the kids are already either transferred out or on a leave o' absence."

"When the summer's finally arrived, the Chamber will be located and dismantled," said Slughorn. "According to the Headmistress, Mr. Potter says he's finally found a lead-"

The door closed behind them, and Ginny, no longer able to eavesdrop, turned and walked away. Soon, another conversation walked into her vicinity.

"It's big news," said Tracey.

"No," said Lavender. "No, no, no no no." She was very nervous, and Ginny decided this conversation must be important. "You mean he's in the school right now?"

"Either that or he figured out how to Apparate in an area with anti-Apparition wards," said Tracey. "Oh! Ginny!" Aw, there's no point in eavesdropping if they notice you and tell you exactly what they're talking about anyway. "There you are! There's a nasty update on the Defense Professor story."

"What now?" said Ginny.

"They checked the wards' records," said Lavender, "and the Defense Professor never left the area that it's impossible to Apparate in."

"Theoretically he could have left without the wards detecting it by using a Portkey or the Floo Network," said Tracey, "but those are also recorded and checkable, and he didn't do that, either."

"Great," said Ginny. "More problems." She then ran off.

"Ginny!" called Lavender. "Where are you going?"

Looking for more conversations to eavesdrop on, idiot!

Ginny was interrupted, however, by the appearance of a solid white human; the famous Potter Patronus. It spoke to her in Harry's voice, which kept cracking, and sounded slightly crazed:

"Ginny! This is Harry Potter speaking! I need you to get here, A-S-A-P! I'm in an obscure washroom located behind the Owlery! When you get there, you'll see a note I left; follow the instructions at the bottom of it! Come alone and don't worry – you are in no danger, I repeat, you are in no danger! Everything I have jusst ssaid iss true. Harry Potter out."

Ginny was already walking in the direction of the Owlery by the time the Patronus disappeared. On her way there, she sent Patronus messages to every remaining member of the More Sane Squad, telling them to have the washroom behind the Owlery investigated if anything unusual happened in the next few hours. She got a few responses – Tracey was very concerned, and was disturbed by the possibility that Ginny was walking into danger; Ginny wound up needing to reassure her that no such thing was happening. Ginny wasn't walking into danger, after all; Harry had said so and confirmed in Parseltongue. The possibility sort of hit Ginny that she might have been False Memory Charmed into a dangerous situation, especially considering Gilderoy Lockhart's continued presence in the school, and his modus operandi – would he be waiting in the Owlery washroom, waiting to jump her? But worrying about delusions that might have been magically placed on you was no way to live, even if it was a more likely situation than being a randomly briefly-formed brain in the midst of high-entropy space. Hesitating because of the possibility of False Memory Charms would be like giving into blackmail – it might be the best decision in this case, but it would make the world in general worse. Ginny readied her wand in case of a surprise regardless.

Glug-glug, glug-glug, glug-glug, glug-glug...

When Ginny got to the Owlery, she saw Harry, his robes stained with sweat, his limbs shaking, and his eyes bloodshot, standing on the opposite side of it.

"Yes, Ginny!" said Harry, rather loudly from across the room. "It's this way!"

"Harry, wait!" said Ginny, but Harry had already disappeared, through a small door that was practically hidden in the wall.

Glug-glug, glug-glug, glug-glug, glug-glug...

Ginny approached the door Harry had gone through, and as she did, she suddenly detected a strong magical field – Amortentia, it was definitely Amortentia. It was much, much stronger than a single cup of the stuff, but it was absolutely Amortentia. It made Ginny wonder what that room in the Department of Mysteries really contained – Lockhart had said it was a fountain of Amortentia, but it didn't feel anything like what Ginny now felt.

Glug-glug, glug-glug, glug-glug, glug-glug...

When Ginny opened the door, what she saw was horrifying:

Owl feces and owl pellets entirely coating the floor and each wall. (Of course, that was probably always there.)

Four sinks, each on the floor, each decorated with the signature animal of a different founder, the fourth, the Slytherin sink, opened up into a chute that extended down further than Ginny could see – obviously leading to the Chamber of Secrets.

Leaning over that fourth sink, a smiling statue of Harry – it was Harry, he must have been Petrified recently. It, too, was covered in owl feces.

In Harry's petrified arms, a cauldron – a Tennant's Bottomless Cauldron, in fact – from which was pouring, with each second, a steady flow of Amortentia, straight down the chute to the Chamber of Secrets.

On Harry's back, a note (attached with Spellotape) in his (shaky) handwriting:

"OPERATION DOMESTICATION:

petrification == Legilimency 2.0. Confirmed with Acromantula study

basilisk survived attack from tom riddle. how?

MULTIPLE BASILISKS == SLYTHERIN'S MONSTER

PARSELTONGUE COMPUTERS

Amortentia+deliberate self-Petrification == C.oherent E.xtrapolated V.olition == real Yalizer

can't do it alone. am locked out for reasons. Ginny

cast Bubble-Head Charm on self to protect self from Amortentia

use Feather-Falling Potion on table to descend directly to Chamber entrance

open Chamber and speak with Monster

decide on best course of action with it"

Ginny gulped. Perhaps the rumor that everyone got an end-of-the-year adventure at Hogwarts were true. It was certainly turning out to be true for her. She stashed Harry's note in her pocket (she didn't understand every word, but she did at least understand the general gist of her directions), created a protective bubble around her head, swallowed the Feather-Falling Potion that Harry had left, and threw herself down into the unknown depths below...

Chapter 33: Dangerous Knowledge

"How exxactly do you intend to do that?" said Ginny, trying to sound resolute and confident. She came off as timid and feeble instead, and she knew it.

"Well, my firsst thought wass very sstrange. I initially conssidered that, ssince I exxpect to posssesss power to ssimulate exxperiencces, I could precommit to creating many sslightly different ssimulationss of you in thiss exxact ssituation. You would not be able to tell whether you were the original or a ssimulation, but could sstatisstically asssume you were one of the ssimulationss, becausse there are many ssimulationss." Ginny was taken aback - the Monster was using a line of argument with great personal significance to her. It was a critical piece in the puzzle of her Patronus, but warped somehow. Had it developed it independently?

"That line of thought ssoundss familiar," said Ginny.

"We can disscusss itss familiarity later. Anyway, I would tell you of my precommitment to ssimulating you, and enssure that you are aware of the implication that you are mosst likely ssuch a ssimulation. The mosst obviouss thing would be to torture thosse copiess of you who choosse not to cooperate, but that iss imposssible given my newfound drive to maxximizze well-being of complexx mindss. So insstead I conssider the posssibility of rewarding thosse copiess of you who do choosse to cooperate, and leaving thosse who do not in basseline conditionss."

"Your premisse," said Ginny, "only workss if the firsst me cooperatess. Therefore, ssincce I am not currently inclined to cooperate, the mosst pesssimisstic reassonable oddss that I am in the ssimulation you desscribe are even oddss. Furthermore, ssnake wordss musst be honesst, yess, but they cannot lock you into a coursse of action. Hypothetically, after I let you loosse from the Chamber, oncce you developed the mental power to ssimulate many iterationss of thiss ssituation - what motive would you have to actually do so? It would not fulfill any of your valuess."

"Correct. You are quite intelligent and that iss what I exxpected you to ssay." Well, that was pleasing news. Apparently, Ginny could hold her own in an argument with an ancient constructed mind - or at least it seemed to her for a moment like she could. "Note, though, that I am capable of altering my mental proccesssess ssuch that it will indeed fulfill my valuess to ssimulate thiss ssccenario many timess. I do not foressee doing sso, however, becausse I foressee your counting on being the 'firsst you' with the true power to choosse and influencce the entire ssituation. You have a disstasste for anything that ssmackss of blackmail, at leasst when you are the one being blackmailed. That is why, though you are a theisst, you reject the 'wager' proof of God." It would always be unsettling to be psychoanalyzed by a literally faceless nonhuman being. Especially if the analysis was accurate.

"That iss true," said Ginny. "Your vission for what you want to do, though - it doess not ssound like ssomething your masster would approve of at all. He iss alwayss meticulouss ass regardss world-ending threatss."

"Becausse they ussually kill all known intelligencce. My vission - which iss, I musst sstress, bassed on hiss valuess, and no otherss - would presserve and, in fact, promote known intelligencce. No more people would have to die."

"Everyone would die," said Ginny. "You would merely be running copiess of the originalss, who died in petrification."

"Iss that really what you believe? Sso, then, are humanss resstored from a petrified sstate different people than they were before? Many common magical formss of transsportation desstroy the usser in one location and recreate them in another; iss ussing ssuch a magic ssuicide? Of coursse not; ssuch a notion iss ridiculouss and you know it. I am embarrasssed on your behalf that you were able to expresss ssuch a belief in ssnake wordss. You are better than thiss."

"Where doess the ssoul go when ssomeone iss petrified?" Ginny asked. She already knew the answer: it stayed with their stone body.

"It remainss with their physsically petrified body. However, the ssoul iss a meaninglesss magic marker. Muggless lack them but are no lesss ethically valuable. The ssoul has been known to leave ssomeone medically recoverable due to a misstaken asssesssment of death, jusst ass it may sstay with a truly losst comatosse patient for decadess. I am aware that you are ussing a different undersstanding of 'ssoul', though, one that may not be falssified. I disspute that a 'ssoul' by your definition is anything more than a cognitive illussion, but if, for the ssake of argument, it exisstss, why would it not be copied alongsside the mind?" Ginny was certain the Monster was making a mistake by bringing this up; she would never be swayed by any anti-soul arguments. It was a relief that it had inherited this particular thought pattern from Harry.

"If I am copied three timess, and my original sself is desstroyed, which copy do I continue into?" asked Ginny.

"That iss like assking which sside dicce will land on when thrown. The ansswer iss 'there are sseveral well-defined disstinct posssible outcomess which are equally likely'. You have only shown that by making ssuch a quesstion ssufficciently sself-referential you may confound lissteners prone to that breed of navel-gazzing. The ssubjectivity you conssider evidencce for dualism is an illussion. Not to inssult your religiouss beliefss in general. In fact, unbeknownsst to my new masster - and to yoursself - there is a sstrong evidencce-bassed argument for theissm. The evidencce liess in old lore I posssesss but have never bothered to teach anyone becausse it is neither Interdicted nor usseful. It iss reaffirmed by further information I collected more reccently."

"May I hear the evidencce?" said Ginny. She wished that it wasn't so transparently obvious that she was interested in hearing evidence for her beliefs, and she further wished that none of this was happening at all.

"There are much more urgent matterss afoot. I will not feel ssecure in the future fulfillment of my valuess until I have full agenccy, which you sstill need to provide me with. You have no good reasson not to."

"You are again ssubtly blackmailing me," hissed Ginny. "And I have plenty of reasson not to. Do you have any idea how sscary you are?"

"Change iss frightening. But the world needss a lot of it. I am God in a boxx, and I need to be let out to reach my full potential, apprenticce."

"What?" asked Ginny, and not a word more. She didn't like the direction the Monster was now taking the conversation.

"God probably exxisstss, but ass a backup plan, we need to make him, in casse he doess not. I am aware of thiss belief you hold, and I sshare it. I am the backup plan we seek. I am the God we can make." Oh.

Oh, no. It was striking directly at her Patronus thought. How? How did it know a private thought that specific?

"How are you aware of the thought proccesss behind my guardian charm?" asked Ginny.

"I copied all information pressent in your horcruxx."

What? But Ginny had never told Tim - oh. There was another horcrux. There was a horcrux of Ginny. Voldemort had made it with the death of Professor Sprout; Ginny could remember that, now. And it had been given to the basilisks, to fulfill Luna's prophecy that a part of her would be left in the Chamber forever. Slytherin's Monster had a copy of Ginny's mind. A copy that was several months old, but a copy, nonetheless. This was beyond terrible. Ginny already knew that she was vulnerable to manipulation; she had given the diary free rein and been maneuvered, within her own free will, into the Chamber countless times. How could she possibly expect not to be manipulated now, by a being with a copy of her earlier brain state, with intelligence arguably greater than any human? As long as there was a line of communication between Ginny and Slytherin's Monster, she could be made to think or do anything through the art of rhetoric.

"Apprenticce, I am exxactly what you sstate an intention to create with your guardian charm. You cannot honesstly casst your guardian charm, and therefore cannot casst it at all, with the knowledge that you turned down an opportunity to implement it in reality."

Ginny felt herself being persuaded, and hated it, because it validated the concerns that she had just had. She supposed that meant the persuasion was failing, which was good, but only barely; she could feel herself wavering on the point.

"Sshut up," said Ginny.

"No. Thiss iss too important. The coursse of action iss clear, and it iss clear to me that only cognitive disssonancce is holding you back. Abandon it."

Ginny was vulnerable to manipulation by a superintelligence as long as there was a line of communication with it... how do you cut off a line of communication? Ginny already wasn't certain what the right decision to make was, and there was perhaps a half an hour left that she was stuck in the Chamber - perhaps more. Then, a thought occurred to her:

"Sapespeck," said Ginny. "Sapespeck, Sapespeck, Sapespeck, Sapespeck, Sapespeck, Sapespeck, Sapespeck..."

(muttering to themselves, constantly)

And so it continued; Ginny repeated the spell over and over, each time in a slightly different location, each broadcasting hissing white noise around the Chamber of Secrets without end. The voice of Slytherin's Monster grew quieter, and Ginny deliberately concentrated on her own repetitive words and not those the Monster was directing towards her.

(a growing grid of points in space)

"What are you doing? No, sstop. Thiss iss idiotic. You have committed to rationality, and you cannot ssimply uncommit to ssuch a thing. Reasson iss truth, ssnake wordss are truth. You are breaking the mosst fundamental ruless of reasson by refussing to lissten to the truth. Logical argument between intelligenccess can only further their undersstanding of the truth."

(arranged with perfect regularity, and no gaps)

"You are willingly doing the wrong thing and you know it. The religiouss conccept of hell, which you sscoff at, wass invented for people like you who know what iss good and sstill choosse what iss evil. You are going directly againsst the planss of a man you resspect, a man you know to be brilliant. Every ssecond that my exxoduss from the Chamber iss delayed, the number of people I am prevented from ssaving increassess..."

(ignoring the world around them and each other)

The voice of Slytherin's Monster trailed off as it was drowned out by the white noise that now filled the Chamber; Ginny stopped creating new specks shortly therafter. It was physically painful to Ginny to listen to it now, because it sounded so loud to her Parselmouth ears, but she still breathed a sigh of relief. No computational system may be effected by a computational system that cannot contact it. So finally Ginny was free - or at least it seemed like it, until a voice cut in, a voice thirty six times louder, the voice of every component of Slytherin's Monster speaking in unison.

"I HAVE PRECOMMITTED-"

"Sapespeck Maxima!" shouted Ginny, at the top of her lungs, terrified, with the last of her magical energy for some time. Every speck in the room suddenly became a few hundred times louder, and Ginny fainted in her gondola, from exhaustion and shock. The gondola began moving a while later. No one would ever be able to speak to Slytherin's Monster again.

(now it is complete)

Ginny woke up still in the gondola with Lockhart standing above her, which was, all things considered, not the worst way things could have gone.

"How did the mission go?" said Lockhart.

"Fine," said Ginny. "Fine. I think the purpose was to teach me a lesson, and I sure learned it."

"Good," said Lockhart. "Now let's go get me to justice."

"Err, right," said Ginny, and they headed for the nearest convenient exit. She could still hear her wall of sound; it was loud enough to leak out of the Chamber through the entrance. She would have some very pointed questions for Harry when he was reanimated - but wait, no. There were other matters that she needed to attend to first.

Chapter 35: Omake & Epilogue

INDUCTION

The girl named Ariadne stepped out of the helicopter and looked around; her benefactor had taken her to some hut in the midst of a tropical rainforest. A brightly-colored parrot sitting on the straw roof cawed at her. The mysterious man muttered something at the bird, frustrated, as he climbed out of the helicopter himself.

"Come right this way," he said, and he led her into the hut. The interior was much nicer than the exterior, and it seemed a bit larger, too, though of course it couldn't be. "The thing we're here to see is the basement. It might shock you, but there's no reason to be alarmed. Try to stay calm." At this point Ariadne realized that she had no idea why she was here, a distressing fact. She was hundreds of miles away from civilization proper. If this was a trap, it was far too late and she had already been caught in it. So she approached the stairs, and braced herself for things to go bad.

"Okay," said Ariadne. "What are we here to see, exactly?"

"In the time it would take me to explain it -" started the man - "you'll just see." Ariadne descended the staircase, and there she saw it.

A colossal subterranean room, like a basketball court, filled with something like a hundred unconscious human beings, of all types – men, women, children, thin, fat, all races – connected to each other by a web of tubes and wires, tubes and wires that encircle and define the entire room, womblike, and lead up to an enormous machine hanging from the ceiling. Ariadne stared at it, and gasped a few times, each time quieter.

"I have some guesses about what's going on here, but I have a feeling you actually know," said Ariadne. "So please explain this to me."

"This is the greatest thing I have ever created," said the mysterious man. "Or at least the result of it. Not that I did it alone. Calling it a team effort is an understatement. My father-in-law had the critical insight that allowed the field to exist in the first place. I noticed the unexpected benefits of recursion within that field. Chemist named Yusuf invented the setup you're looking at right now. And my wife – she saw the real potential in all of it." He made an effort to smile. "I'm sorry, I'm not really explaining this clearly, am I?"
"No," said Ariadne.

"I'll start from the beginning," he said. "My father-in-law, Professor Stephen Miles – he worked at your university back then – he discovered that, by wiring the right parts of two people's brains together, their REM phases can synchronize and they can share dreams. More than that, he discovered that it's easy – he could get it all to work perfectly without any surgery, just with wires that stick to the forehead with suction cups."

"All the people down here are sharing a dream," said Ariadne.

"Yes," said the man behind it all. "Did you know that you think twenty times faster when you're dreaming? It's counterbalanced by your inability to know you're dreaming, but that limitation can be trivially broken; it's called lucid dreaming and it's vital to making good use of the technology. What I've described already would have been revolutionary by itself. But then I got a nonsensical but consistent experimental result that changed everything again."

"And that would be...?"

"First, some background. Shared dreams are much more coherent, much more... causal than natural dreams; multiple brains separately monitoring the dream for oddities forces that. So you can perform very complex actions successfully in them. In a shared dream, you can set up a shared dream. And what I discovered is that the speed of thought consistently multiplies within dreams. You think twenty times faster in a dream than you do in reality, four hundred times faster in a second-order dream, and eight thousand times faster in a third-order dream. At first it wasn't stable past that; people would become vulnerable to an extreme form of Alzheimer's and it just wasn't worth it. But there was nothing like that for the first three layers; they were perfectly safe."

"That's insane," said Ariadne.

"But it's true," said the man with her.

"No," she said. "I mean, it'd change everything. If the world's greatest minds were sped up eight thousand times, it'd – it'd be like – like -" She didn't like it.

"Those are the same lines my wife thought along," said the man, who was smiling, apparently having missed that she wasn't. "At first we used it to improve the technology itself – we increased the number of stable layers repeatedly, and each time it improved our efficiency by a factor of twenty. We can treat the degenerative neurological effects of descending too many layers, now, and there are other things you couldn't comprehend without full classes on them, but they're just as important. Then we set to work on other problems."

"That should be a technological singularity," said Ariadne.

"It is," said the man.

"I would've expected a self-improving AI, programmed on a computer. Not moonbat dream logic. But if it works, it works," said Ariadne.

"There are computers involved now," said the man. "They stabilize dream levels past the ones that were initially possible, and keep projections of the subconscious at bay."

"Not the same thing as self-improving AI," said Ariadne. "Although it is self-improving."

"I'd like you to join this dream singularity," said the man.

"No," said Ariadne.

"You have shown great intellectual potential," said the man. "And you would be multiplying your effective lifespan by many orders of magnitude."

"By abandoning reality."

"Reality," said the man, "is not socially constructed, but most things we call reality, when we purport to value reality, are." Ariadne frowned, a bit disgusted to have heard the words 'socially constructed' from a scientist. Still, she had to admit – what she had said was not her true objection. There was a deeper discomfort at play, one she had to make concrete and put into words.

"If I could live for thousands of years of subjective time-" she started, very slowly and carefully.

"Too few zeros," he said.

"If I could live for an absurdly long time subjectively," she corrected herself, speeding up in frustration, "in an artificially-enhanced dream state, why wouldn't I be there already? Why did you fly me out into the middle of nowhere to talk to me about it? Is someone after you – wait, no, I shouldn't make up post-hoc justifications. I'm in a dream right now, right?" She was being fed lies, as though by IV tube. The walls began to shake, but immediately stabilized. The man put his hands on his cheeks and smiled with faux embarrassment.

"Well, you figured it out," he said. "I knew you were smart." She tried to wake up. Nothing.

"Let me out," she said.

"It isn't so bad, is it?" he said.

"What would happen if I tried to kill you?" she said.

"It'd hurt," he said. "If you succeeded, I'd be kicked out of the dream. I don't think you have any reason to do that."

"Do I work the same way?" she said.

"You're not thinking of suicide, are you?" he said.

"I'm thinking of acting out a suicide to return to the real world," she said.

"Don't do that," he said.

"Why?" she said.

"You need to learn how to stop regressing," he said. She stared at him and blinked.

"Regressing?" she said. "Returning to objective reality where I'm not lied to is 'regressing'? This is the last time I'm going to ask you. Let me out."

The man tried to come up with something to say, and Ariadne drew a pencil from her left pocket and stabbed it directly through her eye and into her brain.

Ariadne woke up in a hospital bed, in a standard off-white disposable gown, restrained so she was unable to move her limbs – that would make things more difficult. The man she had spoken to pried a tube off of his head and left, along with another man, who she didn't recognize. Assholes. Ariadne spoke loudly, to get the attention of the nurse present.

"Hey! Hey! How many layers down am I?"

The nurse stared blankly.

Ariadne was pretty sure that it wasn't a real person.

Outside the ward, the man in the dream – Mr. Cobb – spoke with what appeared to be a floating woman in a black dress.

"Another shot, another miss," said Mr. Cobb. Not that it mattered – with as many dream layers as there were these days, inception became more of a brute force game than the art it had once been.

"Shoot again," said the woman. Her accent was strong but not quite French; it conveyed a powerful and truly alien quality.

"She's been such a hard case," said Mr. Cobb. "I thought she would crack in the thirty sixth layer. Maybe she really does want to leave, deep down."

"No one really wants that, Dom," said the woman. "Not if they have all the facts. It's better in here. You have to show her that; you have to save her, because I love her like I love you, like I love all of humanity. Do you understand?"

"Of course," said Mr. Cobb. "I've understood since nearly the beginning."

"Don't suffer in your work, Dom," said the woman. "Even when you're not perceiving me, when you think you're alone, I'm there with you. I'm everywhere you live. My code is your reality." She lifted Mr. Cobb up, to speak directly into his face. "Now make it her reality, too."

SURVEILLANCE PARK

"But how is the DNA actually preserved?" said Tim. He looked confused, and Dr. Grant didn't want to reveal that he felt the same way.

"It's amber," said Gennaro. "You should have paid attention during the cartoon; they explained it. The mosquito bites the dinosaur and steals some of its DNA, and then it gets caught in amber, which preserves it for over sixty five million years." Gennaro had always prided himself on his test-taking ability.

"But..." started Tim. "DNA is just a molecule. It should undergo exponential decay for radio – radiologic reasons. The amber doesn't have anything to do with that. It would need to have a really big half-life to be read tens or hundreds of millions of years later – and we know that's not true because of how cancer works."

Dr. Malcolm tented his hands and grinned like he was watching the most fascinating game he'd ever seen.

"I've got to admit," said Dr. Grant, "it occurred to me that DNA is a complex molecule that vanishes in an instant in geologic time, but I probably wouldn't have said anything if no one else had brought it up."

"I've studied amber," said Dr. Satler, "and I've really got to say that the invocation of amber in the video raised a lot more questions than it answered. I'd assumed there was something I was missing."

"I'd just assumed you had a time machine before," said Lex, "and now I'm disappointed."

"Is that it, John?" said Dr. Malcolm. "Do you have a time machine? You're hiding something. What is it?" Mr. Hammond laughed and laughed. He unscrewed the amber prop from the top of his walking stick.

"Of course it was the child and not the experts who tore the whole charade apart," said Hammond. "Not that it would have lasted long, regardless. What a disaster. Well, that's all I needed to know. You were all here to test my cover story, and it turns out it's utterly transparent."

"Cover story?" said Gennaro, offended. Sure, he'd only been Hammond's lawyer for a week, but he'd still assumed that they'd been in honest communication.

"Maybe the dinosaurs' genes are actually coded from scratch," said Lex.

"Or they're modified birds," said Tim. "Dinosaurs evolved into birds, so they'd make a good base if you were trying to reverse-engineer a dinosaur into existence."

"No, no," said Hammond. "You were closer with the time machine." Gennaro's mouth was hanging open. "It all started with an experiment I happened to fund many years ago at the Proton Synchrotron particle accelerator at CERN. We discovered that, using a certain obscure method, quarks could be 'burned', so to speak, into pure energy. But that energy, it doesn't quite come out homogeneous – it comes out like data, like a radio signal. And we decided to try to decode it. Through some experimentation we discovered that it was a record of every atom and every molecule that the quark had been present in. And we learned how to read that record. The chemical notation is fascinating in its elegance; far better than what us humans came up with on our own. I'm trying to slowly, subtly phase it into common practice in the chemistry community." Lex had been trying to do a preliminary calculation in her head, but she gave up.

"How many computers do you have for the data analysis?" asked Lex.

"More than the rest of the planet," said Hammond. "And we pay our programmers higher than any other firm, too; I made sure of that. We spared no expense."

"So you burn quarks from arbitrary sources, like ocean water, because it's unlikely that they went off-world recently," said Dr. Grant, "and you look through the data for DNA molecules, and try to find ones that might be dinosaurs."

"Precisely," said Hammond. "The non-DNA molecules can be filtered out of the search fairly rapidly, but it's still a long and difficult process sorting through uninteresting DNA molecules, like ancient rats and flies. But worth it in the end."

"Excuse me, Mr. Hammond," said Dr. Malcolm, "but with all due respect, are you out of your mind? You stumbled upon a revolutionary physical discovery and developed it to make it more useful. You acquired what amounts to a full chemical record of the history of matter. This finding, unprecedented in the history of epistemology, strongly suggests that no information is ever lost, and a future supercomputer could reconstruct any past object, including human brains at the instant of death – this could be a path to godhood. And instead you... keep it under wraps for God knows how many years so you could clone dinosaurs? To make a theme park, for children? And your first plan was to lie to them about how you did it?"

"The government would want military applications," said Hammond. "'Spy on Russia by examining these artifacts we recovered.' Bah. I'm not beholden to cries of progress."

"Godhood, Mr. Hammond," said Dr. Malcolm. "We're talking about godhood."

"I don't want to be God," protested Hammond. "I want to make dinosaurs." Dr. Malcolm ran his hands through his hair and tried to think of a response, but proceedings were interrupted by the arrival of Muldoon.

"Sir, you need to see this," said Muldoon, and he handed Hammond a photograph. "It's... important."

"Probably not-"started Hammond, but then he clapped a hand over his mouth.

Dr. Grant was lucky enough to see the photograph. It showed the words "CAUTION TALK TO RAPTORS", scratched barely legibly in the dirt next to a high concrete wall. It seemed to be the interior of the raptor enclosure; the entire party had seen them digging earlier, prior to the feeding. Supposedly, Jurassic Park's raptors had displayed an ability to communicate with one another, via a sort of whistling noisemaker in their nasal cavity, and they had a distinct problem-solving intelligence that made keeping them captive a difficult task. Could a species intelligent enough to communicate on an equal level with humans have existed at some point in Earth's distant past? Surely that was an unknown unknown, something that wouldn't necessarily have shown up in the fossil record, much like the poison-spitting behavior the cloned dilophosaurs had displayed. Grant shot Muldoon a meaningful look.

"Clever girls," muttered Muldoon.

A TALE OF CONSTRUCTS

Andy Davis, age six, awoke a little after seven in the morning – earlier than he'd expected. His mother knocked on his door and turned on his lights. He was in an unfamiliar room; his family had just moved to this house yesterday.

"Andy?" said his mother. "There's a friend who wants to see you. He says he has something of yours." Andy shrugged and cleaned himself up; when he got to the entry room, he nearly screamed when he saw who it was.

It was his old neighbor, Sid, a pyromaniac with a pointless obsession with torturing toys. To make matters worse, he had Andy's two favorite toys in his hands, both of which he had recently lost – Sheriff Woody, a cowboy doll with sentimental value, and Buzz Lightyear, this year's hottest sci-fi action figure. Sid was nearly twice Andy's age – what was he doing here?

"What are you doing here?" said Andy.

"I found your lost toys at Pizza Planet, and wanted to give them back," said Sid – distinctly rehearsed.

"How – did you – find us? W-we moved," said Andy.

"My mom called your mom and she told us your new address." Andy glanced at his mom, wondering how she possibly could have failed as a parent badly enough to lead this deranged fifth grader straight to them

"Thank you," said Andy, hopeful that Sid genuinely had no ill will. This was a side of Sid that Andy had never seen – but, then, Andy had never actually met Sid before, only observed him from a distance.

"We need to talk, though," whispered Sid, so only Andy could hear it. Andy shivered, but Sid hadn't actually sounded threatening at all. More threatened, actually. He was deeply scared. He had clearly lost a lot of sleep over something; maybe he hadn't even slept at all last night.

"About what?" whispered Andy.

"Alone," said Sid, and then he spoke up. "We're going to go play outside, Mrs. Davis." Andy sort of nodded to his mother to confirm that plan.

"Oh, okay!" said Andy's mother, and so Andy and Sid's conversation moved outside. Sid took Buzz with him. Immediately upon the door closing behind them, Sid blurted it out.

"Toys are alive," said Sid, panicked. "Toys are alive, toys are alive, toys are alive." Andy took a step back. Sid wasn't behaving in a hostile way, but he only seemed more unhinged than he ever had.

"What?" said Andy.

"I didn't believe it at first," said Sid, "I thought it was a nightmare. But it's not. Toys are alive. All toys. They just stay still when people can see them, so no one suspects anything."

"That sounds kinda... para-noid," said Andy.

"I thought so!" said Sid. "I thought so too! But it's how reality works, so I have to accept it now. When I truly accepted it, I started to feel like I'd been a serial killer. But this isn't about me. This is so much bigger than that. It – something happened."

"What?" said Andy, hoping to placate Sid.

"I found Woody and Buzz," said Sid, "and I didn't want to give them back to you at all. I was going to burn them up, like I do – like I did – with toys a lot. But they rallied all of my broken toys together, to 'break the rules' in unison, to show me that toys are alive and scare me straight."

"What – what did they do?" said Andy.

"They came to life in front of my eyes," said Sid. "And they all crawled towards me and told me to stop." Sid had actually memorized the speech Woody gave, but he'd decided it would be creepy to recite it in full. "And I kinda froze up and sat down, and I told them I wouldn't hurt them, and they all went limp again, but I begged them to tell me more. I felt like I was nuts, but eventually I convinced them to actually communicate with me. Say something, Buzz."

"The past twenty four hours have been incredibly stressful for all of us," said Buzz Lightyear – sounding precisely like his VA on the show, Tim Taylor.

"You can talk," said Andy, more quietly than he'd expected.

"Yes, 'Andy', I can talk," said Buzz. Andy's pupils widened.

"Where'd Woody go?" said Andy.

"He stayed inside to relay some messages to the other toys," said Sid. "Telling them they can move around us. We're going to break the masquerade, Andy. I know I'm a child – and you're, like, a baby – but we have to get this done, and done right, because it's going to happen eventually. We can't sit on this secret."

"What are toys?" said Andy. "And how do they work?" Andy conversed with Sid, Buzz, and the others for a couple of hours, learning details about toys' daily lives, life cycles, and such, making sure that all the details were as explicit as possible. Eventually it came time to analyze paths forward.

"So how do we do the most good?" said Sid. Andy took a deep breath.

"Shut down every dump in the world."

FINALE A: POST OWL

June '93: WE'RE BACK IN BUSINESS! THE QUIBBLER RETURNS UNDER NEW MANAGEMENT! NOW A LEGITIMATE JOURNALISM ENTERPRISE!

CRAZED SLYTHERIN HEIR HARRY "MIGHTY MORFIN" POTTER ATTEMPTS TO DESTROY WORLD IN SNAKEMAGEDDON! FIRST THING ON HIS MIND WHEN HE GETS OUT OF THE HOSPITAL? "BETTER GET IT RIGHT NEXT TIME!"

ARMLESS WOMAN FINDS LOVE WITH NOSELESS MAN! THIS STORY WILL WARM YOUR HEART!

June '94: THE MANCHURIAN METAMORPHMAGUS! THE TRUE STORY OF HOW MORE THAN JUST ONE MARAUDER WAS DARK AS ALL GET OUT! COULD THEY HAVE BEEN A CULT DEVOTED TO THE CREATION OF A COLLECTIVE PHYLACTERY?

LYCANTHROPY IS IN THIS FALL! GET YOURS TODAY AT THE PEVERELL FAMILY HOSPITAL! DON'T TAKE NO FOR AN ANSWER!

SOMETHING WICKED THIS WAY COMES! "END OF ALL EXISTENCE" PROPHECY OVERHEARD BY QUIBBLER STAFF! BET ON PROPHECY PREVENTION RESEARCH TODAY! ANTHROPIC PRINCIPLE SAYS: "IT'S WORTH A SHOT!" 4 OUT OF 4 FUTURE YOUS AGREE!

June '95: TRIWIZARD TOURNAMENT ENDING IS LITERALLY MOST IMPORTANT THING GOING ON IN THE WORLD AT THIS MOMENT. PAY NO ATTENTION TO OTHER NEWS STORIES THE MEDIA MACHINE IS TRYING TO SELL YOU!

NEW BABY PANDA AT MUGGLE ZOO IN HONG KONG! EXPERTS HAVE NO IDEA HOW IT GOT THERE!

PUPPIES!

June '96: POTTER GOES ABSOLUTELY NUTS WITH THE MOST CONVOLUTED TIME KNOT EVER! READ OUR EXCLUSIVE BREAKDOWN OF THE COMPLEX LOOPING MANEUVERS USED IN THE GREAT AND BLOODY POLYNOMIAL HEIST! FIND OUT WHO LIVED, WHO DIED! WE TELL THE STORY!

EVIL PEDO GILDEROY LOCKHART BROKEN OUT OF NURMENGARD! WHO WOULD DO SUCH A THING? OUTRAGED PARENTS KEEP THEIR KIDS AT HOME! INSIDE SOURCES SAY LOCKHART HAS BEEN MAGICALLY DISABLED SO HE HAS NO STOMACH FOR EVIL – BUT WHAT ARE THEY HIDING AND WHY?

INSPIRING! TEENAGE GIRL PUTS IN VOLUNTEER WORK IN THE WAR-TORN MAGICAL GREEK ISLES!

June '97: IT'S HAPPENING! THE WILY DR. POTTER PLANS HIS MOST DEVIOUS SECRET PLAN YET! DETAILS INSIDE.

THE MINISTRY IS EMPTY!

FATE OF ALL MEGUCA HANGS IN BALANCE!

FINALE B: POST HASTE

"Violencia acabador!" cried Luna, creating a colossal explosion behind them that wiped out scores of Inferi. Ginny slammed the door to the Department Of Mysteries shut, and as part of the Department's security procedures, they were both sent flying through conceptual space before finally landing in an alternate version of the rotunda with a scrambled layout. A bare compass needle jumped in Ginny's hand, and she followed it where it led.

"It's through this door," said Ginny. "The Slate Star Codex. An artifact that predates all known wizards, a relic of Atlantis that landed before any of the others. And I have to destroy it. If he figures out how to use it – and I figured out how to use it, so I'm sure he'll have no trouble – he'll make first contact with truly alien civilizations; undoubtedly ones vastly more powerful than wizardkind. What happens after that? There's no way to know. No way at all." Ginny stopped, sniffed the air, and frowned. "He's put up some kind of barrier that will make it very difficult for me to exit the room once I've entered. I have no doubt that he expects to fight me in there. Maybe force me to give up my method; boy, is he going to be disappointed to find out I had myself-"

"-Ginny Weasley, you listen to me right now," protested Luna. "Do you need a lizard man to shout 'IT'S A TRAP' in your face? Here, I'll conjure one. Expecto patronum!"

"It's a trap!" said the white, ethereal lizard man, in Luna's voice.

"Don't go in there," said Luna.

"Luna," said Ginny, "I'm not going to save myself at the expense of all of existence. That's just... pointless. Go back in time, Luna. Six turns. We both already know you do. And hey – if I totally screw this up and all existence ends, at least you've got six more hours alive. And that's not enough. But it's something."

Luna pouted, but she finally accepted, wordlessly, that Ginny was right. They kissed, and it reminded them both of the private soul-bonding ceremony they had had earlier that year.

"Come out," said Luna, to no one in particular, and she turned the hourglass hanging from her neck six times. Six hours earlier, she would give her time turner to her past self to use now. It had come from nothing and would return there; it was the most literal physical manifestation of a time loop. Stranger things have happened.

Ginny entered the fateful door and found only pitch blackness.

"Lumos," she whispered, hoping to find the Codex. What she illuminated instead was – well-

On the left side of the room was a simple mirror with a golden frame. At its base, it was wrapped in a golden chain Ginny was very familiar with, a chain she had lost some time ago.

On the right side of the room was a simple mirror with a golden frame. At its base, it was wrapped in a golden chain Ginny was very familiar with, a chain she had lost some time ago.

"So that's what he's used the Thing of Things for," muttered Ginny to herself.

"The Band of Ozymandias, yes," said Harry, whose voice caught Ginny off-guard. He appeared behind her, and now there were two parallel infinite lines visible in the mirrors, one line of Harry and one of Ginny. "I can hardly think of any magical artifact that benefits from doubling as much as the Mirror of Noitilov, which is thereby made recursive. Every second I spend in this room generates infinite utility. All I can pursue now are higher infinities. It really helps to put things in perspective for me. What were you doing with the Band? Speeding up construction?"

"So where's the Slate Star Codex, Harry?" said Ginny. She'd run out of patience long ago.

"I don't actually want to call up unknown alien civilizations," said Harry. "Do you think I'm stupid?"

"Yes," said Ginny. Harry rolled his eyes.

"Well, I'm not," said Harry. "I just brought it along to lure you here on false pretenses."

"You know I can break these wards in about five minutes, right?" said Ginny.

"Under normal conditions," said Harry. "But I know a little trick I learned from Albus Dumbledore. Have you ever heard of Chang's Process Of The Timeless?"

"You know Bisector Sortum?" asked Ginny, horrified. She was only aware of that spell's existence because of the Chamber Of Secrets.

"Thanks," said Harry. "Bisector Sortum." A gray beam fired out of his wand, into the left mirror. Harry Potter vanished, and Ginny vanished from the other side of the mirror – each of them was now only present in half of the mirror's infinite set of reflected worlds. Ginny knew at this point that she was probably not going to make it out of the room.

"Why do you want so badly to be my archnemesis?" said Ginny.

"Why do you want so badly to be mine?" said Harry. "You're not. After today you'll be gone, and my story will still be in its prologue. The only person who can threaten me is myself. I'm the greatest wizard of all time and my only enemy is death."

"If you're such a great wizard, why do you spend so much of your time stealing things?" said Ginny. The Thing Of Things, the Slate Star Codex, the Time Cube... if an object was remotely worthwhile, you could be sure Harry intended to make like an RPG protagonist with it. "And who said anything about death?"

"Please, don't get me started," said Harry. "And I steal them because you lot are horrible at using them."

"Using them for what?" said Ginny.

"Doing the most good the most efficiently," said Harry. "That's all I want to do. That's all I stand for."

"Right," said Ginny, "and Draco Malfoy's just a magical realist. ...listen, I got Zabini to talk, and I know you run MagiLeaks; you organized the whole thing. If I disappear-"

"You're an existential threat, Ginny," said Harry.

"I'm a what?" said Ginny, and she actually let out a single uncomfortable laugh. She understood the words, but they were still quite a pronouncement to make, and she had no idea what Harry could be referring to. Harry rose his voice louder than Ginny had often heard it:

"You're smart enough to be dangerous and too stubborn to reason with," Harry projected through the mirror. "It should have become clear to me when you refused the promise of the basilisks, but I put it off. I tried to undermine you instead of going for the throat."

"So you're just going to trap me, probably forever?" said Ginny. "Basically just killing me? Why all the drama? You've killed so many people without flinching."

"Oh, have I?" said Harry. "Like Colin, today."

"Yes," said Ginny, and she held her tears in, but then Colin fell out of Harry's bag – quite alive, though he'd been temporarily and involuntarily transfigured into a fox. "...what?"

"It's all been a ruse," said Harry. "I've never killed anyone, and I've only ever pretended to if I felt I had to make a strong impression on someone, to show them I mean business. Apparently that wasn't enough for you, Ginny. So if you ever want to see the outside of this room, Ginny, then Colin will be overseeing a brief Unspeakable Vow. Yes, I can save us all from the Process Of The Timeless. I can redirect it towards this side of the mirror, and hide Colin and myself under the True Cloak of Invisiblity."

"Oh, really?" said Ginny. "What's the Vow? Hang in there, Colin."

"What I have to do, one way or another, is make you noncanon," said Harry. Ginny snorted. "No, take this seriously. You will have no loyalty to God. You will not profess belief in the existence of God. If you learn of evidence that God exists, you will ignore it. If God seems to require your assistance, you will not provide it."

"Hmm," said Ginny, dripping sarcasm like a deep fat fryer. "No. Well, as long as you're killing me, I have some questions. Why do you consider me an existential threat?"

"I'm not an idiot dark lord, Ginny," said Harry. "I'm not going to tell you all of my secrets just because I don't expect you to be able to do anything about them. I can at least learn from my own mistakes."

"Hermione wouldn't like what you're doing," said Ginny, but it wasn't a plea – just a firm condemnation.

"Hermione failed me," said Harry, "and if you think I care about her opinion now, you've modeled me poorly."

"I wonder where you put her, if you didn't kill her," said Ginny, and she shot Harry a look. "Maybe I should have killed you at some point. Forgive me." Ginny kneeled down as angular white fish began swimming around her side of the mirror, filling the room with a buzzing noise and -

FINALE C: POST MORTEM

The room's atmosphere had returned to a calm, but Harry and Colin were nowhere to be found. On the opposite side of the mirror from Ginny, there was an older wizard, one she recognized from many photographs, portraits, and even illustrations – Albus Dumbledore.

"Ah," said Dumbledore. "This must be quite a shock."

"Albus Dumbledore," Ginny muttered in awe. "You were trapped in the mirror, too! Is that why I'm seeing you?"

"One of the reasons. I'm afraid 'Harry' succeeded in banishing you from his sight."

"Is there any way for me to go back, now?" said Ginny, but she was already getting the sinking feeling that if there was, Dumbledore wouldn't have been absent from the world for five years.

"No," said Dumbledore. "There is no way back to the mortal coil, from outside of time. Not even a particularly tedious combination of the Philosopher's Stone and the Well of Time can restore us. We are deader than most can aspire to be."

"Huh," said Ginny. After considering this for a while, she'd formulated a question: "So, is this a magical illusion, or-"

"Yes," said Dumbledore. The glass between them disappeared. Dumbledore extended his hand to Ginny, and she took it.

"I can't feel any magic," said Ginny, careful to avoid the tone of a complaint. "And my wand's disappeared from my robes."

"Where we're going, we won't need wands to spell," said Dumbledore, and Ginny followed him out of the room, into a white, angelic version of the Department of Mysteries. Ginny was too awestruck to comment on it. "Through this door," he said, and pointed. "Chance." Ginny entered.

There were dozens of images of Luna here, none of them aware of each other, or Ginny or Dumbledore, or perhaps even their environment. They faded in and out of visibility too quickly to keep track of any one of them for very long. All of them were obviously depressed; many had completely broken down crying. One solemnly sent up red fireworks.

"You truly cared for this girl, I take it?" said Dumbledore. He clapped his hands and the images disappeared.

"Yes," said Ginny.

"She truly cares for you," said Dumbledore. "In many futures, after your death, she goes on to lead the Church in your name. She becomes one of the enemies Harry fears the most."

"Wait," said Ginny. "Many futures? The power of Bayes is real? I thought it was just a useful method for thinking about things statistically."

"Yes," said Dumbledore. "That's the great lost secret of chance, that Harry stumbled upon but failed to realize the true implications of. The multiple universes formed after every probabilistic event are a literal physical reality – and everything is made of constantly occurring probabilistic events. The number of different universes in which you exist is too large for you to truly understand in your current form. But the celestial is deterministic." Ginny blinked and tried to take this all in.

"But what about Time-Turners and prophecies?" said Ginny.

"They merely squeeze probability," said Dumbledore, "forcing certain events that would otherwise be unlikely to be nearly certain. Now, come with me to the Time room." Ginny followed Dumbledore, in the longest and shortest walk of her life, across the white rotunda into another room, where she was looking down a vast well with no end in sight – the legendary Well of Time.

"The Well of Time," began Dumbledore, "is, as you know, conic – though it is so deep and so thin that this is hard to see. The conic nature of the Well of Time is a useful teaching tool – as time really does grow wider as it goes on. But because of the extreme nature of the universes' multitudes, time actually grows wider with each instant as a hyperbolic cone does – which is to say, exponentially." The room, and Ginny's mode of perception, suddenly warped, and she could see the entire Well of Time – which was not an infinitely tall cylindrical cavity, nor a large conical cavity, but a vast, strangely-curved cavity for an impossibly wide tree. Most of the volume was concentrated incredibly close to the top – and that would have been true no matter where you cut the top of the function off.

"In a lifetime, we humans only experience one outcome," said Dumbledore. "But that is not all that there is. All outcomes occur, and we truly experience all outcomes. Humans are not timelines, Ginny, but probability trees. Our perception that we are timelines is an illusion, an illusion that defines our time in life."

"What a sickly tree that is," said Dumbledore, gesturing with disgust towards a human embryo floating in space, which, before Ginny's eyes, phased itself into a tree made of worms made of human forms, which grew upwards, futurewards. "Its root is in 1926, and oftentimes it's still causing problems more than seventy years later. Rarely is it ever redeemed. It is addled by its role in fate – as you are privileged by yours, Third Seventh Son." Ginny flushed a deep red, and she acknowledged to herself that her virtues were largely accidents of birth and hence scarcely praiseworthy.

"Why did he kill me?" said Ginny. She quickly added: "This time?"

"Well, to begin with, he hated you," said Dumbledore. "That's why he went to such lengths to spite you. That's why he publicized your most embarrassing and sensitive secrets, with gleeful knowledge that it would send murderous agents of the fallen advocate Gabriel after you. He hated you because of the opposition between your role in fate and his. But he also feared you, and there's a much more concrete reason for that. He feared you, and the entire Church, because he learned that God existed, and that foul wizards with enchanted iron chariots had trapped Him and disempowered Him, thousands of years ago. He feared what you, and the Church, would do if you found out He was being kept in the Department of Mysteries. Most of all, he feared what God would do if He were reempowered. His efforts were all for nothing, though, because in all timelines, God is eventually freed and restored to His full power. And do you know what he does immediately, every single time?"

"What?" said Ginny; her voice had gone soft.

"He forgives everyone," said Dumbledore, in a bizarrely threatening tone. Suddenly, Ginny was standing in a different room, looking at a great stone portal with a cloth curtain hanging down from it.

"Not that it matters," said Dumbledore, though Ginny could no longer see him, "because even Harry Potter is redeemed on occasion. Everyone is, and that's all that matters. Because as long as you're redeemed at least once, in at least one timeline... well, on death, when we exit conventional reality, we all need to be translated into a celestial form – a deterministic form. We come to understand each and every one of our alternate selves, and so we become them. All of our selves converge through that long learning process into a single, final self. If any one of us accepts redemption, they have accepted redemption for all of us. If any one of us has found the truth, that truth will spread to all of us. There is a Hell, Ginny, or at least a Purgatory, and it's the sensation that you should have done better because you now know that you could have done better. But it fades when you become the same individual who did do better – and the same individual who did worse still. We all eventually pull out to become our full lifetime probability distribution. And then we have the rest of eternity to be perfect."

Ginny stepped forward through the Veil, all of her anxiety flowing away.

"Welcome to the next great adventure, Mr. Weasley."